[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
what's up party people this is Jacob
from the internet today's recommendation
as I love to give recommendations at the
beginning sometimes the end of the old
podcast here is going to be learning to
respond not react by Tara brach t-ara br
ACH that's on YouTube and Spotify and I
think just wherever else you get your
podcast I follow her on Spotify just a
wonderful but the pasta teacher she
tells great story is relatable for all
ages I think it's it's certainly
something that's great to have on when
you have kids around so I don't think
there's any cussing anything like that
in there so great to learn about those
emotions she has tons of those so
learning to respond not react by table
rock today the combos with Scapa say pia
it's wonderful fantastic conversation
can't wait to get into it hope you're
having a great day drink some water take
care yourself breathe from your belly
and stand up straight let go chickadee
chick it's your boy Scott on mic yo yo
yo yo Scott I would imagine if you
unplugged everything in here and then
Sasha alright get it all working again
it would never get back well I probably
figured out eventually
no no me oh you yeah like if you just
unplugged everything put in the middle
of room and then was all you want try it
yeah three two like it but I know it's
so funny a lot of the times I'll like
you all act like I don't sometimes I'll
be like oh it's clearly you just do this
I'll just plug it in and I'll explain it
to someone and then like I don't even
know not only the name of the thing you
just said but like where
located I don't know the numbers that
were look hit with the thing that you
said so you were just asking me what
podcast I like listening to I do I
listen to a good amount of Joe Rogan and
kind of like wherever that sends me I
like like clicking through comments or
like if he reads a book or somebody on
there is is an author I'll check out
their stuff or if they have a podcast I
like Aubree Marcus podcasts i like tim
bile you never heard of impact theory is
his he's from Tacoma actually really he
is the one of the cofounders of quest
nutrition okra yeah tempers Tim Ferriss
yes I liked it first yeah D listen Tim
Ferriss a little bit yeah I mostly go
down like the comedy train okay what do
you listen you because I listen to Bobby
Lee okay Bobby Lee yeah yeah
so Bobby Lee listen to the fighter and
the kid I listen to Chris D'Elia
do you like Chris D'Elia yes I think I
know who he is he kind of has like my
link well yeah he's up now but yeah but
but if your hair was down yes if my hair
was done if you could pretend yeah if I
could pretend your hair was down if you
could picture my hair down let me just
fix it which it is if anyone's listening
since you don't know but you never know
what's gonna happen here you know we're
talking about sharing a beer and holding
hands already
I might lay down down yeah we'll see
what happens so ladies and gentlemen we
have Scott's a Pia yes we do I'm happy
to have you man um I'll just I'll just
tell what I was saying earlier I always
like asking Shay because Shaylee knows
you a little bit more than I do
we've had each other on Facebook and
stuff but she last night I was like
what's was what would you what comes to
mind when you think of Scott and she was
just telling me good people you're just
good people we're talking about your
family or really or saying the same
thing you just seemed like a good dude
and I totally have to agree I don't know
you a ton but I'm pretty hyped to get to
know you and have like a long fun
conversation we just shot a few few
hoops in the in the in the old junkyard
love driveway court never girl and I
mean I I don't I don't remember the
exact numbers but I think I was like 21
0 that I beat you yeah I think it was
multiple games yeah so you claim to know
something about basketball I don't yeah
it's all line
it's all lies everybody tell me a little
about yourself
well first off uh thank you to Shaylee
that was very nice definitely yeah good
people
yes very nice what year did she graduate
from our long she was two guys 10 2010
so say I'm saying OK in you were two
years ahead of us yeah so I'm almost
dead yeah yeah the natural causes your
pet to look at the gates yeah coming up
on 30 scary but yeah so went re long
from Longview grew up in Longview and
then after re long went to Lewis and
Clark College in Portland to play
basketball mm-hmm which is a division 3
college in the North West Conference so
that there's a bunch of schools in
Washington Oregon that make up that
Conference Whitworth Whitman PLU ups
George Fox Pacific Lynn feel I'm
probably missing some but played there
for four years when I got done or was
finishing up there I posted on Facebook
that I was graduating with a
communications degree and was looking
for a job and if anyone knew of anything
in that realm to let me know and so I
think I had like a month left till
graduation and like five minutes after I
posted on Facebook Josh Wilson who's
from Longview went to mark Morris was a
big-time basketball star here the direct
message mean was like hey man I have
this idea it sounds crazy but you know
I've kind of been testing the waters
with it and I think that you and I
together could could do some things with
it was roots awesome and so Josh and I
got to know each other through this
summers basically everyone that played
college ball from the area when we would
come home we would work out together
because we needed to make sure that we
returned to our colleges like you know
in tip-top shape and ready to go so Josh
was kind of the guy you know he was the
best player from the area and he was
older than us and so he took us under
his wing and basically just worked us
out every single summer with him
and sort of like drakey myself there was
a few other people that would kind of be
in and out but Dre and I were mostly the
ones that were like with him every
single day and so we built this
connection with Josh and then when I
posted that you know because of those
summers that we worked out together he
knew kind of what I was about and who I
was and knew that I had a you know a
good understanding of the game and
worked hard and yadda yadda and so he
proposed to me the idea of roots and I
said yes because I had nothing nothing
else to you know to do yeah I was a
graduating in a month I needed to figure
out a way to make money and yeah Josh
gave me the only idea that I had moving
forward and I also knew that if I moved
home I could move back in with my mom
and that would save me like a year of
rent yeah and so I was like okay I don't
have any other plans like a perfect
opportunity or every opportunity to save
money
yeah and to get my feet underneath me
and I really enjoyed Josh I think he's
an awesome guy and so that's kind of how
that like and rightly so so how'd you
take it from just you guys meeting up to
work out into into roots yeah so
obviously that's a long story but right
when he how about when he originally hit
you with the idea what was the idea is
it different than what it is now yeah so
the original idea was like hey I think
that we can make money by working out
kids okay and so like a kid would come
to us and pay us to work them out and
put him through a basketball workout for
like an hour yeah anything and he said
I've been doing it a little bit you know
all the different places that I've been
just to make a few extra dollars and I
think there's a big need for it in
Longview Longview Kelso and so I had
never had a trainer like as a basketball
player it was always just like my dad my
mom like them helping me with stuff or
if I was on a team that coach but I
never had like a skills trainer it was
kind of a new idea and so when Josh
proposed that to me it made I knew what
was but it just I wasn't sure if there
was actually a need for it right because
I had never used one you know Dre had
never used one the people that I knew
never used one and so that's that was
his idea he was like hey I'm seeing that
trainers are popping up here and there
mm-hmm there's nothing in long because I
think that we could be those people and
so that's that's like the idea that
started snowballing yeah that's that's
super excellent that's cool that you
guys were we're seeing you know you saw
no but he especially saw an opening and
he's like we can really do this and then
now it's turned into I mean you're still
very much involved yeah it's his turn
into so how many years ago was that from
like the the message and the meetups and
at the beginning yeah how many years ago
was that so we started messaging each
other probably in like 2012 okay and so
like eight years ago and Josh had been
doing it very in a very different
version but like on his own two years
before that so roots is technically like
10 years old now um he kind of was
calling it roots back then but he had a
few clients he had like one or two
clients here and there and it kind of
was built on the back of when Josh was
growing up he had a guy named Roosevelt
Smith who was the head person at the
YMCA and Roosevelt was the assistant
coach at Lower Columbia for basketball
and Roosevelt kind of took Josh under
his wing and worked him out for free for
years and years I I can't remember how
they got connected but he would go from
the YMCA every morning at like 5:30 or
6:00 a.m. before school and Roosevelt
would just work Josh out and so Josh
always had like this feeling that he had
to give it back to the next generation
because you know this guy did all this
amazing coaching for him for free he
wanted to figure out a way to like pay
it forward essentially that's incredible
that's almost the payment for that guy
to be and to be doing it for free it's
it's your full circle yeah the way
things work so what do you guys do as
far as location wise at the beginning
how do you start things out
boys yeah so essentially we would just
like try to get in any school we could
get into so we were like we were
probably you know janitors worst
nightmares when we would pull up to a
school at like 7:00 p.m. and the
janitors see us walking up like it's the
last thing they want to see Oh dad two
guys that want to use the gym while
they're trying to clean up and go home
right you know so we would go to like
Kelso high school or re long high school
or you know middle schools nearby and we
would use it until we got kicked out
right and so oh you know like the first
couple years it was us bouncing from gym
to gym getting kicked out from you know
one location driving to a new one and at
that time there wasn't this thing going
on and so the schools didn't really
understand what we were doing there
wasn't really a process in place to like
ensure that we would have a space
lockdown for a certain amount of time
which is tough cuz when you have clients
and you say hey I'm gonna work you out
from 8 to 9 p.m. at cascade middle
school and you go to cascade and then at
8:05 you get kicked out what what do you
and your client do you know so it's like
the first two years were tough we were
just like yeah learning we were learning
the schools were learning the clients
were learning we were all trying to
figure this process out together right
were you guys getting business wise were
you getting clients like from Facebook
were you posting on Facebook was it
pretty much because I think a community
like like ours has a lot of momentum and
just word of mouth honestly like yeah
word of mouth and and social media of
course usually like this person who
knows this person right do you remember
how you guys were we're getting new new
people to train and stuff yeah I think
you know Josh did a great job he was an
amazing trainer so every client I would
kind of learn from Josh like he would
work out the clients and I would be like
his assistant for a long time I'll just
be there to help and so any client that
he had originally like let's say he had
five kids to start those kids were
telling people what I was good at at the
time I wasn't great at the basketball
coaching at that moment I was learning I
was really good at social media
and so I took over the Facebook and then
once Instagram and Twitter were really
popping off I took those over great and
that's I think kind of how things
started to multiply right yeah that you
know that stuff's important I had I had
my friend max on yesterday and and we
are talking about some something that
I've heard said before I kind of
reiterated it the you know Facebook you
I do my fair share of like social media
sucks get away from social media but
it's also has this goofy annotation this
like this cute little Bluebird and this
little F you know yeah it's this funky
thing but it's also it's a wonderful
tool in so many ways and a lot of us
know how to use this tool just by
growing up like our age like growing up
having social media having access to it
like you you were fairly fluent in it
and so when this opportunity comes up
it's like how could I contribute more
than more than like just letting my ear
waiting for an opportunity you have this
social media I think to its I was like
really pointing out that social media is
such an important thing for a young
entrepreneur like just starting with
your small community you know your
connections like you don't have to have
your first post have a hundred different
hundred new clients lined up or whatever
but you just follow your community and
it'll take yell or not right it's so big
and it's almost you know like it was
almost helpful be in a lazy way too it's
like would I rather go talk to a hundred
people in person
or send out one post at a hundred people
will see no you know I mean it's like me
and the laziness and me it was like let
me just do this post yeah you know I'm
cutting through it yeah figure it out
yeah so I also had fun with it like yeah
you know you can work you know with air
quotes on social media from your couch
you know while watching you know a great
movie yeah you know I mean so it's like
well we were done at the gym let's say I
get home at like 10:00 p.m. from 10:00
to 1:00 in the morning I'd just be
working at working air quotes again only
social media exactly and so it was fun
to me you know I think you know Josh
doing a great job on the court and then
I was kind of savvy on the social media
I think those two thing
combined really helped us to like pick
up speed so how did you as your started
going across you guys excuse me expand
in different ways yeah and then
obviously you've probably changed exact
it's not like you only do social media
or something right how did you start to
expand like your job as as a coach
yourself rather yours came along yes so
you know the the thing that we knew from
the beginning was that we wanted to give
back to the community that was like the
big idea if we could make money while
doing it then it was a cherry on top of
course and so I had leverage because I
was staying at my mom's house with no
bills
so I had time I had time to figure
things out it wasn't like I was like oh
man I got to pay my $2000 rent bill this
month let me figure it out like today
yeah I had time to figure it out so I
got to make some mistakes that were
valuable and so we knew that we wanted
to get back we knew that we thought
there was a need for it we knew that we
had a couple different skill sets
Joshua's really good at coaching at the
time I knew basketball but I was
learning the coaching part and I knew I
was pretty good at social media and so
from there our next step was how do we
get our own home and you know the gym
was a problem at that point we're
getting kicked out of gyms we just
didn't have a space that we could call
our own consistent yeah and so clients
were getting kind of upset because you
know in the middle of a workout we're
getting booted out because they need you
yeah in the gym floor yeah so we started
shopping for places and we found you
know like five different warehouses
around calots County that were like
doable for a court but a lot of them
didn't have high enough ceilings and so
for a basketball court you know it
doesn't really matter how wide and long
it is especially if we're just doing
like one-on-one skilled training
sessions but you need to be able to
shoot a basketball high enough so that
goes in the hoop of course and so we
found one space that kind of met our
needs on 3rd Avenue in Longview one zero
one one 3rd Avenue
sweet - and a shout-out to Rodman
reality yes and industrial yeah and
that's really yeah I don't know where it
technically turns from non industrial
that might be like an old person thing
to say yeah I think it's yeah I think we
had to actually go and get it passed by
the who would it be
we had to go in front of someone in
power that's weird that we had to go
meet Donald Trump oh god yeah so dumb
Trump yeah you know this was years ago
so I can't everyone beer together yeah
and yeah so it was in the industrial
area and they didn't want us to set up
shop there because it was dangerous the
cars would be coming in and out where
semi trucks are driving and so we found
this space it was perfect it was high
enough ceilings to shoot in but we had
this one like thing that we were missing
is we weren't allowed to set up our
business there and so we had to go to
the longview who would it be
a city hall yeah I think it was City
Hall okay okay
and basically proposed why we were
moving in there what we were gonna do
it's interesting I forgot the stuff up
about stuff like that yeah loopholes
that you wouldn't think he'd have to
jump through so we had to get like a
certain amount of people to vote in our
favor to make it a place that we could
have business but we ended up getting it
done and we moved into there probably
let's see this is our five-year
anniversary and they're so 2015 so yeah
two years after roots like really
started yeah yeah and so now is in now
the facility like what's what's the
facility that you have there what what
is it yeah so it's it was as before us
it was like a mechanic shop and so it's
now we purchased or we did a five-year
lease on the space we purchased a sport
court which is essentially like a
basketball court I picture it almost as
like Legos you can like pick it up and
move it so if you let's say if we move
to a new
place we could take the court with us
and so we bought this sport court put it
down in there got two hoops bolted in
there and we and we now have our own
home we have this little tiny cozy
basketball gym in this little warehouse
you I would love to see it so only yeah
yeah yeah for sure destroy me awesome
yeah so what kind of who is all there
teaching has as trainers is it just the
two of you still or do you got have you
guys expanded and then also I would love
if you want to talk about just your
guys's different coaching styles yeah
under the one roof yeah so it's actually
kind of in a weird transition right now
I'm currently coaching at Lewis & Clark
College in Portland full-time and Josh
is currently coaching full-time at
Tumwater high school okay and so the two
people that started it or no longer here
which is a bummer but I think those are
results of roots doing it doing well
certainly and so right now Courtney
Eaton is the lead trainer and she played
at mark Morris's from Longview went on
to play at UC Davis and it's just an
all-around stud and she's the lead
trainer and then the director of routes
is James Fraley and James is someone
that's been in the community for a long
time went to Kelso high school his
daughter now plays at Kelso high school
he is a branch manager at red canoe I
believe is his title I could be totally
off sorry James but he is doing a
phenomenal job he's just really good
with numbers he's really good with kids
and just has the right heart for what
we're trying to do and so those are the
two people that are in charge right now
okay
so how often are you what's your
involvement like nowadays anyway yeah so
year-round I'm involved behind the
scenes but physically I'm very involved
in the spring and summer and so in the
spring and summer I try to lead as many
basketball camps as I can and I like to
do traveling camps and so what I do is I
try to get one or two in Kelso Longview
and then I like to start going to all
small surrounding town so I'll have one
in like Toledo I'll have one into the
lake I'll have one in a wok oh and so
yeah essentially right now what I'm
doing is camps that's like my
involvement but physically what is okay
I was never organized sports I didn't
you know wait what exactly happens at
camp like I'm not you know of course I
know it exists and I've heard plenty
about it but but what's your guys's
camps like yeah so so we have two
different phrases or words one is clinic
and that and basically what that means
for us is like a one-day event and then
camps is multiple Day events and so what
would happen let's say Jake signed up
right little Jake with long great hair
okay Jake shows up and let's say it's
9:00 a.m. to 3:00 p.m. we're gonna teach
Jake how to dribble we're gonna teach
Jake how to pass we're gonna teach Jake
how to shoot we're gonna teach them the
rules of the game and we're gonna try to
make basketball be fun in Jake's life
and that's our goal for younger kids
like teach them the basics and leave
them having fun for older kids it
obviously becomes more advanced and
we're trying to teach them like the
nuances of the game and like little
skills you're gonna work with them
individually whatever they need what's
your guys's age cutoff do you have so
usually it's like high school seniors
we've worked with college and pro
athletes but that would be more in like
a one-on-one setting but yeah for our
camps it's like we'll do an elementary
camp a middle school camp and then like
a high school camp okay
did you go to camps growing up you know
a little bit yeah this the sports world
has really changed since our I feel like
it's changed since I've grown up when I
was growing up I feel like it was more
everything was around your team and now
it feels a little bit more individual so
like teams would go to camps together
our teams would go to tournaments
together now it's like oh this one kid
has a skills trainer by himself or this
one kid went to a camp by himself how do
you feel about that I don't love it yeah
I don't love it seems you you want each
person to individually like scope
selves like we want you to show up to
this team it's the best version of
yourself course but you know there's a
little bit of a different goal yeah it's
kind of weird it's I wish there was a
better balance of it I I don't love the
idea of like a kid going to a skills
trainer five times a week
and just doing one-on-one workouts
because it's a team sport of course and
so if you're constantly just thinking
about yourself and what you can do
you've kind of lost sight of what the
actual sport is right and so to me like
the a great balance would be if a kid K
massage skills trainer to try to tighten
up some of their skills but then did
team activities like four days a week
mmm I feel like that would be like a
good balance oh okay so how do you get
when you're working this let's say
one-on-one yeah with somebody the the
mindset behind like like where they're
at and where they can get better and if
they K you can be focusing more on the
team let's dive in a little bit of the
mindset what what's usually your your
first base you're like let's let's see
what this person needs like like how can
I help this person be a better
basketball player better better yeah
yeah I mean it even goes deeper than
that sometimes I'm trying to figure out
if if they are even in wanting to get
better or if they just want a safe space
to exercise right or if they just want a
place to have fun and dribble ball and
and smile you know so the first thing is
like are they even here to really get
better like should I be coaching them
like that or should I be should I be
more like a supporter and like try to
build this this space that the that you
have fun and so I'm trying to figure
that off it's very important to know on
your and I like that you said that
that's that really hits me hard I feel
like just knowing because you know some
of them do had different goals like Rome
or just so you know want to go one way
and that's all that's what they're there
to do right and that that is important I
feel like because each person is gonna
be different yeah I mean it took it took
a lot of time to figure that out I
started having kids come to routes that
I would ask them like oh hey how's your
high school season going
and they would go oh I don't play for
the high school team huh and I'm like oh
you've been working out with me for two
years like every day and they're like
yeah I just enjoy coming and it was like
a you know for me it was my mind was
blown I was like oh like this is just as
if you know like I went and I hired a
piano teacher right like I don't have to
go perform I could just learn piano yeah
I don't need to be on a team you know I
mean we forget the point of why we're
doing things a lot of the times right or
maybe I'm just having fun doing it yeah
yeah that's that's the end goal so it
took me a long time to figure that out
first but let's say they were a kid that
wanted to grow their skills to play on a
team to get better at basketball then
from there you know we I would do like
an initial assessment of their dribbling
they're shooting their passing their
defense you know try to figure out where
they're at as far as experience level
and then try to attack like there are
three biggest weaknesses and improve
like there are three biggest strengths
so I would do like three of each yeah
that's great yeah I like again just
finding what each individual person's
goal is we were just we shot a few hoops
before and I was just telling you I've
never been super competitive you were
kind of saying you have certain areas
where you've got less competitive as
well I for me I go shoot hoops in my
driveway a lot and I I don't play
basketball and I'm not against playing
with my friends and stuff but it is it's
enjoyable just in my life I don't plan
on being in shape just in case someone
wants to 1v1 me and I got this what /aa
you know but I but just being able to
enjoy you know the fitness aspect of 20
minutes of getting a little bit of
workout in my driveway real enjoyable
and it's cool that you offer that too
you know I feel like I wasn't thinking
like that when I was younger you know
it's cool that there's people that are
younger that are like yeah like this is
fulfilling and I just enjoy this give me
a great way to work out I just want to
be here for this hour and then nothing
more it's so sick yeah it was um it was
a new idea to me that I had to like
figure out I was like oh maybe every kid
that I've seen
has come in to me for a different reason
where when I initially first started I
was thinking every kid's coming to me to
try to get a college scholarship uh-huh
which is not even close to the truth do
you think I get I'm not just like
assuming this I literally don't know
like high school coaches like not just
the ones you know but let's say like
generally high school coaches do a lot
of them do they have similar mindsets as
you do they know that their students
like the think you think each person
like some of these kids yes want to go
to college but some of them are just
here for this reason I don't know I
guess I do see a lot of like on TV and
stuff you see like the angry coach yeah
I don't know how real it actually yeah I
mean I think I think the majority of
them get it yeah I think we're pretty
blessed with some really good people
around here as far as coaches so yeah I
think the majority of the people that
I've been around kind of understand that
concept I think a coach is an important
person in a young person's life you know
likes it like sometimes having an adult
you can trust it's not just your parents
that you can you can go to and and
they're gonna take care of you in an
area that's new to them yeah you know
yeah it's actually cool thing I went
through probably the most life-changing
thing in my coaching world I went
through a it's called 3d coaching
basically what it is is it's like a
class but it's like a one-on-one thing
you would do with someone that's been
through before and so it's a book and
it's it works hand in hand with like
this web seminar so you're reading this
book you're going through this web
seminar and then you have this
instructor with you that's been through
it and so I did this it's called 3d
coaching and my instructor was cane
Ulrich who's a local he works at a
church in town and he's also involved
with FCA which is a like Christian
athlete group and he led me through this
series and it was like it was really
eye-opening basically it was going down
that realm of what we were just talking
about which is
how important a coach is in a young
person's life and one of the things that
really you know caught my ear when we
were doing this seminar was the book was
talking about how one of the most
influential sentences that a young
person hears and repeats to other people
is my coach says dot dot and and it
really grabbed me it was like you know
that is true whatever we do say a lot of
these kids take it as a hundred percent
fact and they take it and they they get
motivated by they get inspired by it and
they you know will do what you say which
is if used correctly amazing if use
incorrectly is very dangerous right
United mean so you have like this
double-edged sword where it's like we
have a lot of power and hopefully people
in these positions are using it
correctly and you know it made me
realize that everything I say needs to
be on point yeah definitely that's it's
so cool that you're willing to step into
that too you know they're just cool a
lot of times we like realize the the
complexity of our positions and it seems
wavering it seems a little scary
sometimes it's great that you're willing
to step into it and like okay I see this
like these kids are listening to what
I'm saying and and you know III have
similar revelations in my own world
where I'm like okay you know if people
are gonna listen you got to give them a
little advice or right don't waste the
time with what they're hearing you know
especially with kids when they like you
said they'll just a lock onto one thing
like this is the absolute truth like
this is a sentence that I'm going to
repeat it may it made me think of Friday
Night Lights the show yeah did you did
you watch that I mean yeah yeah I know
it was on football but they had the
clear eyes full hearts can't lose
yeah I know that's just like a cliche I
think but they the I just remember that
from that movie and like the kids would
always repeat it on this show and run
but the coach would expand on what those
sort of things mean yeah I mean when
you're you know someone's coach
someone's teacher or someone's boss you
have a lot of influence yeah and yeah so
you know early on thankfully I was
you know I was taught or coached by
really awesome people and so I had
really good influence in my life and I
think those people are kind of working
through me now as I'm now a coach which
is sweet yeah it's so cool you couldn't
be as some of the different coaches that
you've had because like me I feel like
I've had so many little you know
guardian angels of sort that pop up in
my life but at the time when you're
young you don't really see them you're
like oh this is a person I know at this
time and then when you as you get older
you're like Oh for like three years of
my life and they were just like teaching
me super important stuff and I lucked
onto that right and that's kind of how
you grow into be so let's let's jump
forward a little bit to to your coaching
now what's how different is life now
from teaching just more coaching
one-on-one in that roots yeah we're
doing that yes so now coaching at Lewis
and Clark College on the women's side so
I'm the head assistant coach for the
Lewis and Clark College pioneers women's
basketball team and so it's awesome I
love it
I absolutely love it my goal right now
is to eventually become a head coach in
that same division on the women's side
and so that's kind of what I'm aiming
for I'm really really enjoying it I
I've learned a lot about women a lot a
lot of about women and you know they've
taught me a ton so I'm really enjoying
it how was that was that was that hugely
different like of course you would just
think going into it okay there's
probably gonna be things I would be
ready for him there's so many things I
can't expect right now just teaching men
versus vote or did you did you teach
younger women before yeah so roots I did
boys and girls okay so yeah so but then
it was a lot this is way more in depth
you know I'm with this team you know it
feels like 40 hours a week right you
know versus like I would see a kid like
three hours a week different different
faces I'm seeing the same faces like
every day what's that what's that
friendship relationship like you know
you're with you you're inevitably kind
of form friendships yeah with so often
of course it's a little bit different
sketch coach and stuff but right yeah I
mean it's you know it's Dave I think I'm
more like big brother to them nice you
know I mean so yeah that we're friendly
with each other but I wouldn't say we're
like friends we're not like you know
obviously like hanging out or anything
but you know they followed me on social
media and they think that's funny and
you know they make fun of what I wear
you know you know I'm a dork to them so
that that whole aspect is funny to me
and obviously you know I have an older
sister and I lived with my mom you know
growing up all the way until I moved out
so I have been around women but being
around you know 15 women every single
day for five hours a day is a whole new
ballgame this is a different world yeah
the ball game is anyway it's new ball
game but they're amazing we have the
coolest kids um you know it's a high
academic school so these kids are really
smart in the classroom and they're just
phenomenal kids really nice kids really
really just hard-working kids and you
know they've taught me a lot yeah for
sure
huh that's awesome that that's cool so
who were as far as on the let's say pop
culture like like Michael Jordan let's
go Nate hands when he was telling me
like he tells me who he is Michael
Jordan is okay who was your Michael
Jordan who were your influences outside
of your like the the wonderful coaches
in your life yeah who's my Michael
Jordan that's a good question should we
like in the coaching world can we in the
coaching world it doesn't have to be in
the coach on Canada I guess that was a
pretty big bridge to gap yeah let's just
go Jordan you know okay so you know I
obviously speak my parents as like
superheroes you know for the longest
time I always thought they were like
superheroes like invincible like right
so I'm not even count them I'm not gonna
count they're just up there they're just
inevitably R in a different world um I
really liked Magic Johnson growing up
who played for the Lakers and the reason
I got into him is my dad would have
these v hv HS tapes which for younger
kids go ahead and
but you know watch a video yeah I'm
watching a video on YouTube about what a
VHS it's a weird so weird and so I
really got into him as an athlete I
thought he was a really really cool he
had a ton of charisma he was always
smiling he played with a little bit of
Flash and I'd like to that about him so
I wore his number in high school I
thought he was really really cool but as
far as like in the coaching world like I
kind of looked up to John Wooden who was
the famous coach from UCLA and the
reason I liked him is he seemed like one
of those guys that his players would
invite him to like their weddings you
know what I mean it's like okay it's the
guy that they would call 20 years later
to see how he's doing and you know tell
them tell their coach that maybe they
were like having a kid or fantastic and
so to me that's like in the coaching
world that's kind of who I want to be I
want to I want to be the guy that gets
invited to a hundred weddings that's so
beautiful fetus a guy like Lee said that
man I I I think that it's important I
just like bring it up because I think
that it's important for any kid of any
age to like allow yourself to have a
mentor and like you know if your parents
or you have bigger brothers or people
close to you like look up to them too
and of course you're us but we're just
okay to have like these like how it'd be
cool to be like that one day because you
you kind of grow up and you start making
moves that sort of make it seem like
it's gonna happen you know right who are
that who are your people for that I
don't know man I I'm so influenced by
like so many broad subjects and so many
different things like I've always just
I've always liked a ton of different
stuff yeah what was the first thing that
came to mind honestly the first thing
that came to mind was probably John
Balian okay that wasn't like it when I
was young I didn't like super where it
is the shirt I I have a kind of his
thing tattooed on the back of my neck -
beautiful mind nice yeah that was me and
my buddy Tyler got those coinciding
tattoos but in so so my influence there
is just I like I look up to him
in the form of his just ability to
completely be himself as supposing we
just expresses like he's not afraid to
be like nervously himself or did just
express himself and I don't know I just
like I think it's super important for us
to have idols and have people we put on
pedestals and a lot of times like you
know I find a DJ for a long time I get
caught up in my share of sheriff ego
like hardcore man and a lot of times
when you're so into yourself you you
even like older people who aren't even
in your lane you just see them as
competition in a strange way and instead
of like an idealization and it could be
some sort of situation like you know
that's a great man and I would love to
be you know like him one day right you
know those sort of things right I I have
my sort of daydreams of like who could I
be in the community when I am like 65
like in their similar ways and it's cool
to let yourself think like that broad
term because it gives you you can set
your little stars like I'm gonna shoot
at this right what what would your dream
life look like in five years train and I
know that that can be maybe even a tough
answer but I like that though let's see
my dream life in five years I think that
at this particular moment a ssin is such
a huge thing to me and it's such a an
inner understanding and calling and in
exploring the mind a lot of things are
meditation honestly so five years pipe
dream it would be to either have opened
or have in the area have a meditation
retreat cool not that I'm like super
shooting for that on rebus but if we're
just pipe dreaming the next five years I
think that would be cool what about you
like if you were in your world in the
next five years man the next five years
I would be a head coach of a college
team I would have a podcast you'd have a
podcast I would have a six pack and have
six pack you know
what else what else you know you have
more than just your the meditation orgy
right yeah I definitely do okay listen
let's go back and forth fought back for
it alright let's let's dream musically
in my music terms I want to push myself
DJ wise I want to I want to do things
that I noticed is cliche but I want to
do things people have never seen before
on stones I want to I'm someone who I'm
like I see more and more people not
giving in to the person on stage and
they're like I want it to be like this I
have these expectations I want you know
I want to try it without even mentioning
the word phone I want to give them a
reason to never pull out their phone
because they're so transfixed with
promoting else going on the stage so I
want to do like something very
inspirational music wise in the next
five years live shows live shows okay I
want to do something different life is
let's see my turn in the next five years
I will have a dog in the next five years
so I'm looking forward to that and that
that will require probably a house with
with right now I'm in an apartment
downtown Portland with and you know it's
the size of a porta potty and is it a
porter play it is yeah I don't I don't
pay rent though it's literally a porta
potty but I can't have dogs in there you
know - it's a one of those apartments
where the landlord says no go on pets
there's no it's not big enough for a pet
what's gonna be your dog have you man I
don't know I think I'm gonna be one of
those guys that just goes to the shelter
and like the first one that gives me the
beedi eyes he's coming home with me do
it do it I definitely have and you
probably know too they have like foster
programs because a lot of times you know
maybe the dog just doesn't match up
mm-hmm and I don't want to like
discourage you at all but we did foster
dog for a little bit okay and he was so
cute and so great in so many ways but he
had very bad separation anxiety were
hoping for a dog that we can leave at
home for a couple hours a day right but
anyway we actually ended up getting down
the month we like returned him to the
Humane Society or like unfortunately
we're not going to be the
best fit for him but he got to these
this older couple who was retired who
could be with 24/7 and they know on
Facebook because they knew about it and
like they would send chaley photos every
couple months of it very cool
so you want to get doc you did say I
gotta go back let you to see you wanna
podcast yeah I do want to podcast
what would a podcast be for you to me it
would be it would be me just being able
to talk to people that I enjoy yeah you
know I mean I'm like if it goes anywhere
it goes anywhere but honestly would just
be an excuse for me to sit down for an
hour two hours a week and talk to people
I mean that's why I inspired by it is
like what you're doing is very cool and
when I saw it online I was like okay
it's cool that I know this guy it's cool
that it's an actual professional set up
it's cool that he's talking to
interesting people it's cool that the
conversations are cool
um and so I've always wanted to that you
know like I bought like a blue Yeti
you know microphone you're it maybe two
years ago now it hasn't come out of the
box no but it seems like so much at the
beginning because there is like it's not
as simple as just you sitting for the
mic and talk it's like the setup and
things you need and where do you post it
and how do you post and all that stuff
yeah when all the chords are unplugged
and then everything's in the middle of
room what am I gonna do well you do I
will no I would love to help
you okay like it I so I will all due to
that yes sir you were right here guys
heard of here lock it in and I won't
edit this part out no but I use either
yesterday or the day before he has slept
the day before I mentioned to Shaylee
this same thing I was like I want to
emphasize I want to help get other
podcasts off the ground so I literally
said this so we should have a day we'll
figure out after the podcast cool have a
day let's uh you know maybe the next
couple months we can get you going
doesn't even look that easy and would
love that yeah awesome I'll have to see
if my fourth party has any plugins boom
well order potty before potty plug
alright if I could be the name of the
podcast what I was just gonna say if you
had to give it a name right now what
would it be porta potti plugins
welcome to the roots podcast also known
as porta potti plugins porta potti
plugin Pisapia
it really rolls off the tongue I mean
who doesn't want that shirt outward yeah
have you ever thought of like a name or
anything you know creatively part of me
because I'm going into the world of
coaching that I need to make sure I'm
not saying crazy stuff you know what I
mean I need to I do I have free range so
part of me wants to name it like I'm
learning so like if I do mess up I can
be like yeah that was you know three
years ago I'm learning dude yeah I have
so much of that I have even the first
when I first I posted my first few or
like they were kind of out of order I
live in one of the more first few I'm
like dude I suck at talking like I I
interrupted that person or I did this or
whatever and I was like hopefully people
don't think that I'm just that it was I
said and it was a this whole thing and
of course Shaylee talks she's like
sensible and and it's so funny we think
that like we're gonna put our foot in
our mouth so bad but it's it's you can
only do the best that you can right
right now and it seems like people do
understand that I always dread I would
hate I've already said here a couple
times I think I've mixed up just simple
things like dopamine and oxytocin and
I've done it multiple times as I've
listened to the podcast and I'm like -
nobody cares that was the thing there's
part of me that wants to get hung up on
it right there's part of me that's like
dude I'm just glad that you're doing
this what I'm rounding about here Scott
is I think that you could just get going
on it and just even if you had one
episode like hey I'm just gonna tell you
what's going on here's Who I am I'm not
perfect I just think there's something
enjoyable where I'm gonna do my best
room if there's anything that if you
come on my podcast and you have you want
to make sure I don't go over any certain
thing or whatever bring it up right yeah
yeah I think I think it'd be fun I
really like what you're doing and that
when I saw you doing I was like maybe I
can do it because okay cuz I know him
and I'll I'll make him come set mine up
yes you've got it down
this is perfect uh yesterday I said that
I've been actually just secretly doing
this podcast so Oh strange I was
secretly been doing this podcast just so
I can ask them like hey there was a
zombie apocalypse where would you go
just so I have like some some red spots
on a map so I know Jeff ah yes you say
choise I don't I don't have one for you
sure
let me think roots wouldn't be bad
you're not bad it wouldn't be bad
because there's a lock yeah I'm trying
to think of like vantage points it kind
of depends though it always we always
get to industrial is it the crazy
zombies like the World War Z zombies
where they're sprinting or is it just
like the yeah if it's the them we might
be okay at roots yeah there's a lot of
basketballs we could get a high point
and throw basketballs on them yeah I had
a question for you but and it was
important but now I'm forgetting I just
steamed should we just pause for like 12
minutes we can just see her quietly yeah
okay okay ready set go listen to you
was it do you have anything okay
it's bothering me oh okay I have a hit
area you have any New Year's resolutions
as I do okay so what we do every year
and oh let me forget I want to hear what
your New Year's is like cuz I feel like
people have a great New Year's situation
too so every year we do some sort of me
and Shane Megan a couple of our other
friends you know kind of varies but we
go to like a cabin we rent some sort of
air B&B a few times we've done
snowboarding just like a way in the
woods if we don't have cell phone
service that's super great for new year
so we did we just we did just seaside
this year at midnight we went to the
ocean me and my friend Megan Elam we
sprinted at midnight just to the ocean
and for me I threw away Lac in 2019 and
then I had like a word that came back
that's like powerful to me that I kept
and so we kept on to my word was
authorship so I'm gonna work a lot
riding this that's definitely Hugh's
resolution for 2020 for me but I've also
we've done talking about hole 36 days we
on January 6 we did another thing of
hole 30 just as like a January momentum
to kick off 2020 mmm which is a diet
where it's kind of like paleo you stay
away from all added sugars and all like
the weird stuff that you can't pronounce
in the back of labels and in alcohol and
all that sort of stuff yeah I feel like
that's pretty much like our new year's
resolution situation I think mine mainly
is gonna be that word authorship has
been pretty huge on my mind so I'm kind
of seeing where that takes me
you do want to write 20 articles books
well so I I mean I write every day okay
I growing up before my like let's say
before and littered throughout I kind of
had a little bit of a traumatic
childhood I had I had rough patches in
my childhood but when things were good I
wrote a lot I love to write short
stories and I would like stay after
class and like have poor teachers like
proofread them and edit them for me yeah
and then they just want to get out of
there I did probably but like I feel bad
for this I'll do it again jig he's
writing about dragons again it's great
yeah but I I don't know I you know when
I first started this whole like the like
a year and a half ago like I'm gonna do
this like whatever is in my heart I
gotta just run out at full force
whatever I'm doing here I was very much
like I have to write a book like in the
book to me it's like how to heal from
depression like how to get better why
you should get better all these things
and like I'll start writing chapter one
and it just has eight pages of like kind
of around that subject but it just is
like floaty and I'm not a I didn't go to
school for writing I my subjects I need
a little bit more time to perfect my
craft
rosalie so I don't know if it's gonna be
aa
is in like a book that's published I
read a lot of poetry I wouldn't mind
doing even just like blogs that are ten
minute reads on my site I essentially
have a ton of rough rough draft stuff
and in 2020 I want to
figure out exactly where that goes
that's cool I write every day we got to
figure out where it goes in 2020 cool
yeah cool what about you get give me
your before I forget what are some of
your staples in the whole thirty like
what are you eatin Oh
for me I'm a huge state guy I even
outside a whole thirty a ton of steak so
today for example I had bacon that is
nitrate free so nitrate is I think one
of the additives it's unlike a fireworks
I believe likely Jesus but so 19 nitrate
free bacon steak and hash browns and
there's a certain kind of hash brown so
that you can get that just throw them in
the pan um a lot of veggies there's so
many different ways we have this whole
thirty book the income amazon you just
flip through it and it's like every
picture is like oh I forgot about that
like there's just you know it's like oh
you can have peppers but you forget that
you can have peppers and cut off the top
and fill it with like eggs and say you
know there's so many different intricate
things to eat or there's like paleo
chips they're like banana chips or
plantain plant ancient sorry and get it
font you know get those on Amazon so
like I can still eat chips and stuff
there's not bread whenever so steak
chips are you feeling good oh geez I
feel so good my mental clarity is is I
probably I think I'm missioner - but I
drink less coffee when I'm on a whole
thirty cuz you don't have those bogged
down like for me a lot of times waking
up in the morning is when I feel the
food that I've eaten wrong or I have
like you know a beer - right it's not
the hangover it's like the stomach right
I mean you get it it's like it's like
raw I feel every beer that your drink is
it's not going super well in there you
said you'd heard of hole 30 have um II
like the elimination diet yeah so I uh
I've been playing around with vegetarian
and vegan a little bit okay and you know
I don't feel any different
yeah yeah I don't feel any different but
uh yeah I don't know I I would like to
like get on a really healthy kick I
think for me a whole of variation of
whole thirty would be where
feel best yeah dude I just like the the
mixing up of it forces you to eat these
certain things like so you can't like
have add maple syrup to like
whatever doesn't sound right so it makes
you be creative and it makes you like
spend a little more time with what
you're getting in the I think it has a
little more sentiment sometimes to I
mean it just makes sense you know I mean
like we there are actual real foods yeah
so there's not much more you need to say
just it's just actual food you know it's
so weird because before I had done all
30 out of diets and I hate even saying
these sentences done diets remember it's
a we all have a diet right well eat but
it genuinely is is it changed my
perspective about the things that I eat
and like the way that I eat it flips it
but but I think that any just trying
anything for 10 days for 15 days for 30
and just being Stern about it our
society has so many options and so many
like I don't want this thing I'm gonna
pick this up because I can it's so
available I think it's like super good
for someone you know it's on you I have
ADHD ends for me like sometimes it's not
so great to just let myself Fripp and
have a million options it feels strange
a little more structured and I like hey
man let's let's just focus on this thing
for right now no III haven't done I
would love to try a vegetarian or vegan
for 30 days yeah or something yeah
vegetarians not that hard to be honest
like it like you don't to make many
changes pretty much everything that you
would normally eat you could have just
supplement maybe a beef patty fur but
you know that fairing patty or whatever
but vegans a little bit more difficult
you know like cutting out the dairies
and the cheeses and the all that you
know you really have to think about what
you're doing but yeah I don't know I
right now I just eat like crap and I'm
gonna try to get better you try to get
better yeah but my go-to right now if
anyone is also eating like crap get a
DiGiorno's cheese freezer pizza okay
with me so far I'm in this
on the seventh run time I fall thirty I
mean it's gonna okay gaudí elimination
dad was gonna ruin the elimination so
you get one of those okay put the oven
to 400 21 minutes when it comes out dice
up or not dice I cut up a green bell
pepper couple of them and then a couple
tomatoes put those on top with red chili
flakes and then ranch to dip ranch to
dip - yeah and then you're a happy
camper for about five minutes I'm coming
over so let's do porta potti pizza
porta-potty pizza and we'll do it should
we we might like crap ourselves so we'll
get a roots workout in here - yeah
probably will probably crap ourselves if
we eat all the pizza before the workout
yeah or so we'll work out before work
out before and then we'll feel deserving
of our yeah and then we'll we'll cancel
the workout out with our porta potti
pizza and that's how it works but you
know and then if you start to feel bad
you're in a porta potti already so
you're ready to rock it just painted
yourself into something in a porta potti
so fast I mean you can like almost touch
like wall-to-wall in the middle of my
quote-unquote living room man yeah are
you how are you about that you're you're
a low temperament person like a pretty
content
yeah I'm just I don't need much I think
I got that from my dad awesome I I just
don't need much I need like if I have
like $24,000 a year I'm I'm good dude
I've been yeah I I'm with you on that I
I think that there's like there's gonna
be times in my life where I'm like okay
I'm ready for for money because I want
to do something with it but I don't know
I've been pretty content with just like
you know like I'm able to get a good
book on audible when I'm when I'm you
know in like afforded beer-brewing Road
you know sort of things it sometimes we
we grasp for all this money everybody
wants all this money and it's like
sometimes you don't need all the money
that's just more stuff to deal with
sometimes right the the only thing that
I think would be really cool I'm sorry
I'm reading that TV was to say I'm
broken out I can still be used for nice
and broken back and still oh nice there
you go
I love that but the only thing that I am
bummed out about not having money is I
it'd be cool to like just make other
people's lives
cool
like imagine if I gave you 30 million
dollars today what you could do for your
friends there are not even friends just
like people that need it or even just as
small as like I would like to leave a
hundred dollar tip to this person yeah
who just gave me a great day this girl's
so sweet like I would love that and yeah
that's that's the bummer yeah like if
that's the only thing that I I am like
man maybe I should chase money just so I
can do that okay so the first let's say
our first wish
there's no genie we just found a lamp
we're rubbing it boom boom boom genie
comes out our first one is already we
already got whatever amount of money so
we can do all these cool names we just
said we only got two wishes left you
only got two wishes from this genie I
would rather - okay do you have one off
the top of your head well I'm thinking
weird you know idea okay okay I'm
thinking that I I thought I had it was
Foreman it was some sort of like concert
venue of my own but it was just really
exciting and now I'm second-guessing I
feel like if you only had two wishes I
would be so indecisive I know that was a
real really the first one that came to
my mind was that you would be able to
snap your fingers and transport to
wherever you want all this snap your
fingers hey just because like then I
wouldn't have to fly anymore you know
like but you think you would do some
lazy and be like coming to go over
there yeah you're just sitting on 20
yeah you would end up doing that you'd
be like you'd be like from bed to shower
shower to couch couch to bed I wouldn't
even go to like oh well this stuff how
do clothes work in those situations like
how do your clothes know that like I'm
also a part of this human ability to
come with us person and then you show up
naked to the nightspot you're like oh I
got this power but that's not register
the genie didn't tell you he's like well
you didn't say anything about your
clothes like so there's not really
specific it makes me naked literally
every time yeah I don't know maybe the
transportation would be cool like snap
of the fingers I mean like you could go
down the suffering and like world peace
I'm like you know I mean I probably
should focus a couple wishes oh yeah
like hunger like transporting naked I
don't know I don't want to give that up
I mean I know world hunger instead
I know there's people there that
literally dog food but I'd rather be
transfer naked to LA today the traffic
you know LA traffic what can you not a
big fan of turbulence yeah I don't know
man that I'll take the transportation
one as my like the one I want okay and
then I'll do the the hunger one like
let's solve that okay cool all right you
got hunger so let's do do one that's
really you know like for you and I'll
get one for the world one for me and one
for the homies okay so my one for the
homies I'm pouring out of 40 of Old
English and the one for my homies the
one for the world is sex trafficking I'm
just gonna end all sex trafficking
however I know I just cuz at in my boy
Ashton Kutcher would be the genie yeah
have you I I've heard that as a headline
you know like have you heard much about
that like how he he funds and like he
helps these people like get out of SEC
traffic and he like exposes like he's
great yeah I mean I don't know much more
than the headlines does he does he have
like an app that he created for it -
that's like helping quite a bit I don't
know I for some reason I'm probably
totally making that up
no no that I mean that seems like the
next logical step of where we're at I
mean I make an app for it but yeah he
seems like he's killing it so a passion
cochairs already he's taking care of
that wish but if I can help him out yeah
I don't wanna put him out of a job but
if I want to help these people right it
ruins his life because I'm you name Jake
got a genie he's like what the hell man
he comes to me homeless native you took
my job was I got transported here by
snapping my fingers
okay what's what's my wish for me uh
what's what's my ability I think I'm
over like solitude so something I want
okay I'm just gonna go with the amorous
clothes so I'm gonna go to the woods
okay yeah so I'm just gonna fix your
idea all right well my idea sucks now
now that you have a whiff clothes
transport you know that'd be fun though
what would be cool yeah I I always go
down like these crazy with my team like
we'll be driving to a game two hours
away and I'll be like would you rather
be in prison for a year or homeless for
a year with no shelter you can kind of
get to know somebody in a pretty good
good way yeah I kind of have my own like
where I'm like oh let's you know I think
we cover the subjects that I thought
initially I kind of throw those out yeah
yeah there's a I mean they get sick of
me real quick
they're like I'm listening to music I've
had it Scott yeah
would you rather Drive and shut up or
yeah do they call you Scott or what yeah
they call me Scott
it has there been any so did you hear my
voice have you tried to get like will
you just respectfully call me no safe
yeah no no I just don't care yeah yeah
like it just seems like a weird thing to
care about I care about like three
things in life and that's not one of
them what are they like I care about I
really don't like people being like
bummed out like I hate like I like it
bothers me seeing someone get bummed out
about I don't know I just don't like
seeing people hurt so that's one thing
family stuff is another quick and then
my DiGiorno cheese pizzas yeah bell
peppers and tomatoes I'm with you and
that I'm gonna say I've been I've been a
cold three weeks by without a pizza it's
really no yeah you can't yeah so it
could you is there a way that you could
there is like yeah the gluten-free crust
toka like a cauliflower crust oh okay so
you could you can't have you can't
cheese but nutritional yeast
this tastes cheesy though yeah it's like
so we had it on these baked potatoes
that we made okay and it's it smells
like the Kraft cheese powder okay which
you know I don't know what that really
is yeah food or it's not I mean it's
delicious
and it tastes great on Sponge Bob shape
magic I don't know yeah actually I saw
that on Instagram so some fitness person
was like putting whatever you just said
some sort of yeast
oh you don't put nutritional yeast yeah
on some sort of bowl and she said it was
cheesy and it tastes good
dude yeast is one of those words that
we're like we don't really know what
exactly it is but if TV is not yeah it's
it's also attached to like something to
do with reproductive something and so
it's also weird but what it's a food
it's an STD you know isn't it also in
yeah isn't it in beer too like it's yeah
yeah I mean it's this word that we're
uncomfortable about Brett I don't know
why yeah it's like moist is it all the
st words moist east though maybe that's
maybe they're just so ASMR dude Shaylee
has this awful list that she likes to
bring up and add to out loud and to have
this this and between her nurse friends
of just terrible words like secretion
and anal seepage those sort of nurse
terms doesn't sound good little seepage
what is that
Shaylee at Shaylee she probably loved to
come in here they can tell you all about
anal seepage for like an hour
she's a savage when it comes to that
stuff like I can't how are you with
bodily not good I'm not good like that I
will you know like if there was like a
dying man knocking about gross blood of
course usually there's this natural
thing get away
icky icky but a dude I'm even talking
about these things or like seeing them
on TV or like show watch surgery shows
and I'm like not only I'm not eating but
I'm just trying to exist in this home
yeah and I don't want to see human rift
open and then they just the sound effect
the sound bars on upstairs and you just
hear that
yeah ASMR body sounds we could get into
it but I have a real big fear of needles
blood I've been dealing with in it's
like going down this weird spiral of
anxiety and I've had to see a therapist
but it's it's a whole thing
are you serious yeah well we can stay
away from it if you really don't like it
but I'll let you know if it gets weird
but right now I'm good okay that's
certainly okay so believe it or not and
needles make panic attacks
they just make my butt super sweaty I'm
so nervous tattoo needles totally fine
with them okay to me like a doctor
needle is very more uncomfortable than
er yeah I
for whatever reason I just cannot handle
it I think that people yeah and sorry
the blood thing started coming up where
basically what it does it makes me feel
like I'm dying if I'm like around it and
I start spiraling mentally right I feel
like I'm having a huge panic attack I
feel like I'm dying and I feel like I'm
happy now yeah that whole thing and so
when I started getting at coaching I was
like well I'm gonna be coaching players
that are eventually gonna get cut you
know we're playing in competitive games
like the kids are gonna bleed at some
point kids kids are gonna boy this is my
dad it's gonna happen and so I was like
I need to get ahead of this you know so
I went and saw a therapist and the first
guy was just not my cup of tea he was
like I go in he did not care about my my
issue okay I thought it was like
basically he was like you was he like
what are you doing
and so his way of yeah I was a weird
approach and he was from Chicago like
probably you know tougher guy than I am
yeah he's different kind of pizza for
sure different kind of pizza he doesn't
live in a port-a-potty but yeah he did
the I think it's called what is a
version I don't know where like he
wanted to bring a bunch of needles and
fake blood and and have me like play
with it like get used to having it in my
hands and like okay and I was like I
don't want to do it was immersion I said
a version okay kind of like dopamine
dopamine oxytocin on this podcast I
always mix it with you and so serotonin
he was like I was like telling him I was
like I'm gonna have a panic attack if
you do that you know like I I came to
you to try to not have panic attack yes
you're gonna give me one more yeah on
the first day that I meet you and so I
didn't go to him anymore then I went to
a new lady she was very nice spoke to me
very quietly to a point where like I had
to get out of my seat so I get closer to
her face till I hear her but she would
walk me through steps of like breathing
and like okay now let's draw and you
know like okay but long story short it's
still a problem it's still a problem do
you think it helped at all like the
breathing helped a little bit like I use
that now when I'm in a situation that
I'm struggling with right but the
anxiety is kind of like spiraled now
it's I struggle if I'm in a situation
that I know I can't get out of so I
believe it's called agoraphobia maybe
where you're in like a public situation
or social situation that you're not
supposed to leave or you're unable to
leave and you feel almost like trapped
and so that's what I've been struggling
with lately like for example if I'm in a
staff meeting at the college I'm
supposed to be there for the next 90
minutes and me knowing that I I'm not
supposed to leave the room for 90
minutes it gets me freaked out well I
you know you say that I'm totally the
same way in so many areas that's that's
super cool so that's kind of what your
anxiety seems to stick on to you it
seems yeah it's it's a yeah it's weird
and I started drinking coffee like maybe
three years ago which is weird super
late you know what most people start
doing it in college when they're like
studying and stuff but for whatever
reason I finally got into it three years
ago at my job at bud Clary and it it
spiked by anxiety big-time but I love
coffee I still like you so I like play
like this devil's advocate of like maybe
today's the day it won't spike my
anxiety no but it always does we always
do stuff like that I that that's one
thing that I always I worked at the
lumber mill for five years and I was on
graveyard or that was so they called it
swing so it's like 4:30 p.m. to 4:30 a
over 4 days a week and so inevitably I
drank a lot of like monsters and gone
but I'd also throw in pre-workout
because I would always lift hours
between doing it and just like a few
years of doing that like my normal was
just like so much caffeine running
through my veins at all times and it's I
would I would be such a dumb dummy I'd
be like there's no way all this caffeine
is
why I can't sleep like it's I mean and
so now I'm always I like kind of like
beating it to a pulp I talk about it
seems like a lot of people when they
talk about them I can't fight its admit
out loud you know the caffeine I do have
a little bit too much cutting that stuff
out it's great for anxiety vain' like
you said that you're just kind of
working with it like yeah I think so for
example like I was a little nervous
about today because uh you know we
hadn't really met right too much we just
had hi a few times and I didn't know
what I was gonna say I was like oh I
might say something stupid today you
know both okay and so normally I would
get a coffee today and I have a day off
I'd like getting up early on Sundays and
like going to the coffee shop and like
doing some work and writing and drinking
way too much coffee but I knew that I
had anxiety for this podcast and so I
was like I can't have a pod can't
have a coffee today
because it'll spike it don't and so I
have to like manage it like if I know if
I'm getting on an airplane in a day um I
can't have coffee on an airplane days I
can't have coffee on staff meeting days
I have this weird like schedule now
we're like dude I think that's smart
though actually you know like I am you
know everybody has their vices like
whether it's whether it's its super deep
and in an illegal vice or if it's just
coffee or social media we all have our
things that we're just old to you know
and that's how we manage our life I
think finding a way to balance it and
finding like things that you did that
you know like I'm not gonna have one
today because I want to I don't want to
add to the anxiety that I'm already
feeling or I don't wanna like I know
that it's likely to sneak in here so you
know they got to the point where so
before our college games they do the
national anthem and so our team stands
up on the court for the national anthem
and if I you know on a day where I have
freedom I'll have two three coffees like
I love it I love it and so when I was
still figuring out my anxiety and I
didn't put the tune two together the
caffeine was screwing up my anxiety
making it go a little bit haywire I
would have you know two coffees on game
day and then we would end up having to
stand up on the court for the national
anthem and for that
90 seconds to two minutes where I knew I
couldn't move I would start spiral
that's where it just hits you and I'm
like I have to stand here I can't move
it be disrespectful if I went and sat
down I was like spot and it's 2 minutes
long like right pull it together you
know it's so crazy how simple we can be
sometimes about that that it's so stupid
yeah and I think a lot of it too is like
I eat like crap right now
you know DiGiorno pizza is shout out
sponsor me I'm on social media all day
scrolling like my attention is so short
alright I'm eating you know drinking
caffeine I'm probably not sleeping it
the best you know I'm doing all the I'm
not working out I'm doing all the things
that you would want to have anxiety
right and so I'm gonna get it in check
in 2020 let's go that's your plan 2020
of that and I'm gonna try to think
before I talk I think before you talk
which I'm not doing good at so yeah I
know you're doing totally fine here I
have a thing that it wants that's don't
think or don't react
oh gosh I'll have to reread it don't
it's like don't think react or maybe the
opposite don't react think and probably
probably that sort of thing don't want
to be don't react think yes guys II
don't want to react but although
although after a while when you have
enough you're kind of like to think that
you're training yourself at all times in
some ways you know every time that you
hold your tongue in weight to say
something every time that you think
really quick just for an extra
millisecond before you say something
it's you know dude we don't know what
we're gonna say right like there's our
brains are just saying a bunch of crazy
stuff all the time and we pick it up and
just say like this is what's gonna kappa
oh my god just stopping to think about a
little bit roots helped me big-time with
like stopping and thinking before I
speak and stopping and thinking before I
post and like hmm I mean big time I in a
big shout-out to my mom she's a she's
been an educator for 25 plus years she
was really big on like hey you're now
being looked at differently right you
know I mean you're not Scott who's in a
college athlete you're now Scott who's
[Music]
dropping their kids off to you yes you
know I mean so you need to be listening
to the right music in the gym you need
to you know and I knew a lot of these
things already but just having the
refresher from her was great like you
shouldn't be posting pictures of you
holding drinks you know you shouldn't
write even though I was of age but like
it says just don't post up you know just
don't post you know my just silly things
like that but it helped big time with me
thinking before I speak I still struggle
with it because I like to be the funny
guy the first so you know the funny guy
is never the guy that says the joke 30
seconds late just a guy who says it
right on time
hey by the way we were thinking that
thing we said earlier what if I said
what if when he said porta potti pizza
then I said yeah so I I struggle with
that and I'm working on it yeah it's
something that again like with it with
his podcast I understand that I have I
mean I kind of have like a whole ripped
open for me like I'm I'm pretty lucky
with like I don't have you know if I can
get younger people looking up to me in
you Shaylee always says like what would
the the 16 year old you need to hear and
I always keep that in mind but the I'm
luckily able to be like super authentic
and sometimes brutal and and you know
like but but that's the cool thing about
a podcast is it is not everything that I
do my guests don't represent everything
that I do like I can have so many
different kinds of people on here right
and they can be themselves and I can be
myself right and yeah the other side of
that too is like now with social media
and with you know every kid has access
to YouTube and everything they've seen a
lot you know what I mean like they're
not dumb yeah
and so you also can't be a so yeah you
know it's like I ought to be honest with
with the kids I'm coaching you know to
an extent so you know like you know like
my I went to Lewis and Clark College
also now I'm coaching there so the the
college kids they'll be like did you go
to parties when you were in college yeah
and it's like yeah I was a kid you know
like
a college kid I don't have to go into
detail about it but I yeah I enjoyed you
know college and yeah probably did
similar things that you guys are doing
like I understand the world you're
living in right I feel like that helps
them connect with you because like it's
it's things that they're really thinking
about you know it's it's not it's not
that you giving them permission just
because you did it you're saying they
should do it revver
there's of course details when you're
talking it's just like when you're
talking to even me when I'm talking to
my nephew it's like a young kid there's
things I'm gonna withhold from from them
but I think just just being relatable I
think you're a super relatable person
just in general I can imagine you
probably do really well with with the
kids too
just being truthful with them yeah I
mean I think if your truth truthful with
them and they see that you're being
honest like nine times out of ten
they're gonna believe what you're saying
and also respect what you're saying
right well exactly have you thought
about have you had the the looming
question of kids yet in your head yeah I
really looked at it yet well yeah I mean
I'm out of that I'm really far away from
it obviously I'm single and you know
nothing on the horizon but yeah with the
ladies ladies hello all or I'm thinking
before I speak this year
call me 2021 you're gonna break up so
you say what you're gonna break up with
whatever girl you meet in 2012
you're gonna stop thinking before you
speak darn it yeah yeah the twenty
twenty-one is full of fights yeah it's
the out of twenty I'm gonna be a great
boyfriend twenty twenty-one I'm just
nightmare yes we'll see huh guys I have
a new resolution twenty twenty-one but
yeah I would love to have kids yeah do
you want actually I've danced I have no
kids okay I have no kids I have my mom
has a cat okay I don't like it that much
it's just at the house I did have a
hedgehog Marilla I didn't like it that
Monica it was it just it pooped a lot
and it ran its own poop and it just kept
running as a meal and they're just poop
everywhere and I got pinkeye from the
from the head talked fly so that seems
like it so it shitheels yeah you would
know porta potti no but I you know it's
something I've always been pretty I
didn't realize that I was like this but
now that I'm more you
taking a look at why I'm doing things
and how I want to live and all these
things and changing what I want to
change I would brush off the kid
conversation like too quickly
mm-hmm I beg no no I don't want to be
like it seems like a waste I would
almost find this a perfect time to joke
about how how kids fart and they're
smelling and they're just slob on it
like you know that's what I would do but
the last year so I've been actually
looking up the question more and I think
I'd do right this second it's like
there's so many things that I haven't
fully worked through now that you can
work through all of them but either way
it is super cool to allow yourself like
as a man like as you get to to an age
like I was so gung-ho I'm like I'll
never have kids there's no way ever now
I'm like no like let's look at that
question let's not make that decision
and kind of really want to be kinda like
we're talking about like giving yourself
like what could that that dream be in
five years like realistically what you
got to give it to yourself yeah I mean
the the kids thing for me kind of goes
back to like I'm working with kids
non-stop and I feel like I'm good at it
and so I feel like I would just be
missing out if I didn't have the chance
to have my own right you know I mean
like I feel like I would be a good dad
and I think I would enjoy it a lot and I
see the joy that my dad gets out of
being a dad and so yeah I think it would
be now the amount of kids and when it
happens I don't know but I would like at
some point I would love to have a kid
yeah do you want to have one yes I think
so today we have life I think okay how
do we is this a stork Oh Mike what is
the same place in clothes yeah he had
all the inappropriate just what what was
your dad like who was he as far as not
even just basketball like were you guys
outside and like had again Junya hoops
yeah so kind of interesting he was 40
when he had me really so he's 70 right
now Oh kind of yeah so he's an older dad
so I think I had a unique experience
growing up like my friends dads were you
know probably in their late 20s when
they had them and so when our
they're gonna gains my dad to be like 60
and their dads would be like 48 you know
47 um but my dad was super wise he was
super kind very very kind and
compassionate he loved sports he wrote
for the Daily News for 25 years was
their their sports editor and so he was
really into sports he would take me all
the games and I just loved it he you
know we he enjoyed doing anything that
involved a ball with me so yeah we we
had a lot a lot of fun he was a amazing
dad yep still is still life still has
awesome
so he'll Disney 7070 I turned 70 in
November so that's a huge you know
milestone he shout out my fellow Scorpio
yeah I'm also November hacks
I don't like know a ton about that but I
just like was gonna say yeah what could
I text my dad later and say hey you're
this it's a he's a Scorpio as far as you
say that yeah you're a Scorpio you're a
Scorpio okay son and it would probably
like change it to scorpion and then it
just all be weird be the emoji did you
guys play other sports growing up too
like yeah I mean like I played baseball
basketball and like I tested like every
sports of football golf soccer like I
taste tested at all but yeah my dad was
always around for all of it yeah he
loves baseball and basketball those were
probably like his two favorites yeah I
did I definitely liked my alone time
definitely my I liked I liked hanging
out at least or like skateboarding yeah
I liked hanging out with the boys and
like that's not exactly a team it's not
as much structure I think you learned so
honestly I think organized sports like
in school I would rather have my child
do that than just that I would you know
force them or anything but I'll act out
on a lot of structure by choosing
skateboarding over over organized sports
but I also I didn't just
circumstantially I wasn't able to do
sports but the the structure that the
sports provide to a young kids brain I
think is really important I mean
a lot of times we forget especially from
young age it's like you're teaching kid
how to interact in the world you got to
teach them a lot of times that what they
think is not the exact same thing that
this that Tyler thinks seen right and
and that's a huge thing that sports can
probably teach in a huge way yeah I
actually saw your video about that I
don't know when it was which maybe like
three weeks ago about talking about like
you know it's crazy that people think
that their perspective on the world is
going to be the same perspective that
some guy in like Afghanistan has right
in the world was that yeah yeah no I'm
talking about yeah yeah we we forget
about that like it's crazy something
that like you can say the sentence but
unless you really think about it it's
like oh yeah like you why would I expect
them to yeah or why should we expect
them to write or like even I got and you
know some guy some woman in Boston how
is she gonna the same perspective as
some guy that lives in a port-a-potty in
Portland the port-a-potty Portland guy
it's completely different perspective
it's completely different lives like and
even at that moment they're going
through something different in there at
that stage in their life I always like
the comparison that I use you ever
watched the show of Vikings it's sort of
newer I've seen it but no I haven't I
just haven't heard of it it's bad ass
for one oak I only watch it I don't know
if you like like Game of Thrones okay
yeah or the Rings yes but it I actually
had it I when I first was thinking about
as I was watching this show and and when
the the Vikings pagan religion I think
whatever they were when when they like
came over to me I'm totally butchering
the names until brain farting but but
England and whatever these people were
like worshipping completely different
gods right and this is like you came up
on a Viking ship on to like castle walls
right and the Vikings like the
Christians didn't even realize that the
Vikings were there to like pilgrim it
like just take them out and take
whatever they want whatever because
they're not even thinking like we have
to fight against our lives like Vikings
if you came up on their shore they're
gonna bust your face they're ready for
it you know the people are living
completely different so in just the fact
that if you really think about different
languages so even the situation like the
Vikings in this situation did not speak
the same language even kind of has these
other people like not even just the
grunts that come out of your mouth are
not are different like if that doesn't
tell you how different your reality is
like we assume that every argument we're
entering in every discussion rendering
in that the person is like you are 100%
as logical as me you learned the same
things as me you grew up in the same
manner as me like you respect the same
mannerisms the body language you
communicated the same body language is
it just crazy man we're so silly
sometimes we forget how different we are
it's crazy I think you know some people
innately have a good understanding of
that and like understand that everyone's
gonna have different views on things and
then I think some people just don't have
that that in them yeah and so you know
it's it's tough because yeah it's like
you know you listen to different
podcasts than I do
we're from the general same area of you
know Longview Kelso and like we're
around the same age you've read
different books than me you probably
listen to different music than me we had
different upbringing just like - us
being from the same little area
everything else is probably different
totally totally you know it's like we're
yeah we have some middle grounds but
we're gonna have a lot of different
viewpoints on things and I don't know it
was interesting when I when I saw your
video about that it was like I'm
surprised more people don't understand
this yeah no it's cool thanks for
mentioning it mentioning and bringing up
I think it's cool to to just reiterate I
like mentioning those things like even
just randomly bringing them up in some
sort of way on the podcast and I always
I like mentioning little things that
pull people out of what they're doing my
buddy Tyler texted me the other day and
he he just said like dude that thing you
do with your left hand in the door
handle
I like that was like what do you do you
saying right now and he's like on your
podcast episode so and so I'm like oh I
don't remember saying that because it's
you know I have even just after 20
episodes I remember clearly but
essentially it was like stopping you're
going out your car and you're in the
momentum and you get out to your car and
like at some point you put your hand on
the door handle
opened it and you perform that function
and you got into your car like but if
you can just stop at those little
moments and like I'm pulling my door
handle up and I know and that's what and
this is my car and just breathe and
you're like I'm outside and that's okay
and I'm this is my life right you know
whatever just stop what you're doing and
all the momentum and even just having
moments like that so I think pointing
out that people are different in certain
ways like that you can almost have those
little time stopping momentum of like
don't get caught up in your in your
differences you know right we're all
just so different right
yeah this is interesting on a sidebar
while you were talking about that
opening up the car door
it made me think of have you ever had
like a long drive where you don't
remember a second of the drive yes yes
and you're like how did I get to Burger
King
do you ever everyday I live now and I
wake up at Burger King so sometimes I'm
like I'm terrified did I kill somebody
and I don't remember it within the last
60 minutes cuz I remember what I was
thinking about in this last 60 where
you're just like almost daydreaming like
it's crazy it's Auto pie you know we're
we're in the number I've heard 95
percent of our day and our actions are
autopilot like we trained ourselves to
be this way and learn this thing or you
know think about when we were a kid we
trained ourselves or learn how to walk
and now we don't think about walking
alone it's locked into the back
breathing when you start thinking about
breathing there's like get anxiety stop
breathing stop everything completely
it might done breathing well that's one
thing that with a lot of the meditation
things I had long periods of where I'm
like dude
focusing on your breathing okay but now
I'm focusing too much on my breathing
and now I'm just controlling my
breathing you know I'd have that so long
but dude if you tried to stop breathing
you couldn't your brains not gonna let
you stop breathing it's one of those
things that you'll stress yourself out
but when it that was just about
meditation but right isn't is isn't
there also the thing where you like
can't break your own arm or something I
don't know that seems to make several
science but like I've heard Britney I'm
right now remake here I'm gonna do it do
it well I heard like your brain won't
allow you to like maybe it maybe I'm off
but so you know what someone comment
below comment below break your own arm
if you have broken
please post a video of it yeah I'm the
comment I guess yeah
Scott definite Stussy it what if you had
to get any sort of shots afterwards if
there's any ladies out there that broke
their arm this year all their admin oh
man I've seen some terrible videos on
tosh point-o about people I don't want
to talk about it makes me uncomfortable
to think about that hey I do want to ask
ya what y'all listen to you at roots
like what you did mention like oh we got
a like you know you kind of can't just
let whatever playlist shuffle all the
time I mean I'm sure how is that process
bin yeah
the world of today made it easier for
you to find music yeah yeah I mean super
easy like for me I try to just like get
up tempo like fun music you know so I'm
trying to like well one if the kids like
it then it's usually then they're happy
so it's gotta be they want to most one
want to listen to hip-hop that has crazy
language and it's oh I have to go to the
alternative of like okay what's like
more of your Justin Bieber ish type
music that I can get into and so
anything that's not cussing and saying
like slap your grandma then which no one
should do
she never should never unless she got
ran over by a reindeer recently yeah she
hasn't wake her up in like cram are you
okay bobbing around it's the only
situation but yeah so for a while there
I was going Calvin Harris radio on
Pandora not bad because it was always
like up-tempo and usually no cuss words
you know you got a little Rihanna in
there Oh little jb i don't know i
usually the kids to do it but write
anything up tempo and and put smile on
people's faces yeah it's kind of hard to
have any suggestions I definitely do I'm
sure I could
I mean Spotify okay so in the DJ world
let's say record box the example that
record box is a program that it's my DJ
crates it's like back in the day when
you had your crates another thing you
put it on there and I am its it
organizes them for me and then so before
a gig my stuff and record box is slowly
being more and more organized or not
totally there but I pull my
the songs I want out of that and I load
them into my other program tractor to
play live and but so the algorithms the
like a is and a GIS or whatever that the
record box program has if I play Rihanna
for five seconds that the song I forget
the name of the actual name of it might
be for five seconds but a if I played
that and it's this tempo and it's this
key and it came out in 2017 and it's
Rihanna who has tracks with Drake like
all these variables and the AG eyes and
the AIS will I'm just saying it
correctly the computer programs will
pull up similar songs it'll suggest
tracks that are just like this right so
for one DJ's are going to have jobs in
two years because the more than that
separately coming out
not exactly but it's it kind of is what
a DJ does but it's great because it for
me I like mixing I like mashing up a lot
of songs so a lot of times I can let
that thing run and like I didn't think
to play that song but it's gonna sound
great and I could use my skills now
roughly I laugh but anyway
Spotify now has very similar and while
these other apps have very similar
suggestions okay so when you go to like
go to radio of whatever it's kind of the
same thing that you get from Pandora and
then they also have the explicit content
from the e but you got to watch out
because of course it's just because it's
a cuss word doesn't mean that it's
appropriate to hear rather everybody
right yeah that's that's a funny one but
I mean the parents are cool like yeah
nine times out of ten I'm just running
over to to turn it down or change the
song but they're like laughing you know
yeah too worried about it yeah it's hard
it's a lot of work to light it and all
the music stuff like like you're not
there to handle all that yeah yeah yeah
I can do it I can text me man we can
hook I can give you a few playlists or
something but you don't don't
underestimate the suggestions on Spotify
or even just searching things like high
school friendly hip-hop or something
like that it's not always gonna be
hittin it can be hit miss because people
can add their own playlist but it's
getting to be pretty broad in their
algorithm Sothis that is cool yeah yeah
it's interesting you talking
like the a I like how it's like kind of
taking over a lot of like the grant work
almost mhm but allowing you to still do
the fun part it's cool yeah it's a I was
discouraged at first I mean I was
thinking about like getting rid of DJ I
was just like not loving DJing and we
can the clubs and stuff and so I was
just like kind of man but now that I've
gotten I've spent so much more time
organizing and being able to like get
back to like okay the craft I do love
mixing and just like playing songs that
don't usually go together and find a
cool way to make them enjoyable is it
like a whole hour-long set or whatever
it was so he had to did that it's
interesting to think I was watching this
morning I was grabbing a sample clip
from Jim Morrison he was predicting in
like the 80s or the 70s or something he
was basically saying like I think that
the future of music is going to be less
band members and more like one person on
stage playing an electronic tape like he
was predicting DJs and stuff essentially
it's enterance live yeah but I just I
kind of wonder I have my own areas where
I want to push just as an artist in the
community of DJing I want to push my
boundaries as a DJ but I'm kind of
interested to see where it's gonna go
yeah thank you that will be interesting
with our talk about like with technology
yeah with the technology like like how
can we like how can we make DJ still
like good and enjoyable and like you
know it's an hour however long you're
gonna go see them it's enjoyable but now
they have this like badass robot
standing next to them a sorcerer bad
does the machine is ten times better in
every way
so exciting right yeah the world is
gonna be an interesting place in ten
years let alone like 20 years you know
30 years yeah have you learned about any
of the like biohacking or any of that
stuff like it like in your world as far
as sports and athletics the athletic
world and technology is anything are you
talking about like even like you know
like gut health I'm like any of it yes
exactly okay the information the
technology that's improving all these
things yeah I mean I not like my level
you know we're not like that in depth
but you know I read articles like I read
last year lebron spent a million dollars
on his body
alone and so I'd love to find out what
that million dollars entails right I
would imagine he's doing whatever the
best is out there and yeah I mean like
they got health stuff I always hear
about different people on Joe Rogan and
the different podcasts that I listen to
just talking about how like your gut
health could even be you know linked to
depression it could be linked to anxiety
it could be linked to cancer kit you
know it could be linked to a million
different things so um yeah I mean
there's so many things that I'm curious
about as far as like health and body but
who knows who's doing what right and
what we should really be doing yeah it's
anyone's guess at this point I know it's
AII just I think it's probably cuz I'm a
little bit of a guinea pig or myself I
definitely am like I'm the first one to
like I like when someone's like aw is
that CBD gonna make you high I'm like I
don't take take the whole file let's
find out like that's not like the best
example of right I go to CBD I do yes
yeah yeah I love to you in the in a
second cool yeah yeah well well let's
just go that way I'm so CBD I don't know
a ton about it I have a couple homies
who in the marijuana world they they
know quite a bit about that and how it
relates because I want to be able to
explain like you know 30 minutes of like
someone who knows nothing about CBD 30
minutes later they know whatever they
need to know there's plenty of that on
YouTube so definitely look it up but I
do have a friend I'm gonna have come and
talk about CBD but for me it's it's hard
to explain what it does because it's not
it's not like you you put the drop on
your tongue and you you just suddenly
don't have anxiety or you feel like I
don't want to move or anything CBD as
long as it's not that the THC tincture
room which is like directly from and
that still has THC in it don't know
exactly again but it doesn't get you
high it doesn't get you stoned it's not
psychoactive it's not psychoactive it's
it seems to it gives you okay so
something bad happens something is kind
of the same thing that meditation does I
would say something bad happens and you
have your initial reaction on
of your reaction right back to it it's
like it gives you a little bit more room
in between that time a little more of
it's not that you don't care it's
difficult to describe in this weather
it's nothing you don't care but it's
it's less reactive it's something that I
think you could take CBD for ten days in
in within the ten days you'd probably be
like I don't know that I noticed that
much but then if you're kind of looking
back on the 14th day you're like how am
i different and then 10 days ago 14 days
ago you would notice a difference and I
know that seems like a terrible weird
weird no I think that's pretty cool I've
taken it a few times in drop form
I think I was getting into it because of
anxiety okay I think I was like that's
why I was like let me see if this helps
and then I started a few Chuy's and I I
didn't do it long enough or like you
know I would do it like one day and
forget like in the next three days so I
needed to like actually get back on it
and try it but that one person that I've
heard you know swears by it for their
kid is Brendan Schaub who's on the
fighter and the kid all right
his kid had seizures was struggling with
seizures and so he got him on CBD and he
has a how to see seizure sense that's
okay and so now he's actually sponsored
by CBN he swears by it I forget what
company it is but I am intrigued by it I
think you know I know that people have
even used it for cancer there's some
type issues I would love to know more of
what it really does and who should be
taking in how you take in you know all
that fantastic yeah did your podcast
yeah I'll definitely you know when I
have that one oh yeah cuz I want to I
know like a little bit of peers in
theirs but I don't want to like
miscalculate what what I'm saying and
try to be like dude I'm not a
know-it-all about about the CBD I do
know that my personal use like the last
the weather outside a day has been a
little rough and in the weather seems to
get me
yeah depression wise and so I have been
so what I do is when I'm like okay I'm
feeling a little a little more low today
I'll take extra CBD or I will take you
me so I don't really fall like an exact
regime it's kind of like as I feel it or
if I'm like today it's feeling a little
rough I woke up kind of like my brains a
little scattered whatever in for me I'm
a little hippie with a lot of things I
do but I'm very much like as I'm
dropping that like try not to do it as
you're running out the door sort of
thing like stop and like what's the
intent here you know I'm like like III
don't know if this is gonna be a magical
thing when it touches my tongue I'm not
expecting it to be but but I really I'm
wanting this to help the intention for
this to help the reason why I'm dropping
this on my tongue is this just I really
believe in that like you know that the
four spasibo whatever you want to call
tell your brain why you're doing it
oh it seems to help man it seems to help
and it's not super expensive and there's
no negative side effects it doesn't give
me the shit's it doesn't taste terrible
it's I think it's it's worth anybody
trying yeah but definitely we should we
should learn more yeah what you just
said I'm carry cells about with that in
food which is the way that you eat food
where like if you're like intentional
about it and thinking about what you
want to do to your body I feel and this
could be told like nonsense but I feel
like when I actually think about what
I'm eating and what I needed to do for
my body I feel better about it
absolutely and my body takes it in
better yes which is is that a thing I
think it's time I think it's totally a
thing I want Turk Jake is that a thing
it is yes according to the millions of
YouTube videos that I watch you also
have you thought that like
intentionality when you're yeah and just
like because you were saying like you
know they take CBD running out the door
like right I feel like when I'm on the
go and I eat my dinner on a pizza while
running then it goes down differently
than if I sit down and praise it and
dude it's a real thing you know I like
to look at like rituals and like what
what are like throwing out baby with the
bathwater with like rituals and
religions and stuff a lot of that stuff
is dogma and weird and whatever
like I like little things like what
about the people Jehovah's Witness for
example I think they're the ones that
they say name the Father Son the Holy
Spirit amen
when they have a small prayer before
they eat where we yes that's like within
their religion like that's that's there
they're praising for their God but I
think that just the way that our bodies
work setting that intention of like you
know what I am thankful for this food
I'm thinking about this video game that
I was just playing I'm think about
article I'll just reading that momentum
that sometimes we sit down at dinner
with is a million thoughts and just
stopping and like you know whether it's
a prayer or whatever people have before
they eat it's just setting that
intention it's it's gotta mean something
and it's again like all like the YouTube
holistic psychologist that I that I
learn about it seems like the the mental
the placebo we brush off it's that we're
like oh it's that's just a placebo I
don't know though and it's like wait but
it worked
Mariah helped it helped even one 0.05%
helped do it man do it rich life a
little better it like does it does it
does it make your life worse to stop and
try to like you know what let's just
think a good thought for 10 seconds on
purpose even if it feels dorky and fake
and whenever but also sometimes you got
to run out the door Nate did you want us
pizza on the run what YouTube dives
have you been into lately what's like on
yours what's in your search okay so I
actually start starting on the whole
thirty I have been on like a youtube
break in a youtube break
I still use YouTube because like so when
I play piano for example I like to have
like sounds of waterfall and then you're
like nature sounds or something so I use
it and smallest is like that or like I
need to watch tutorial on this audio
thing so I pulled up but I get pretty
lost in the just searching YouTube and
like letting the algorithm suggest me
something good the hothea that know me
so well thank you so well but i like
there's a guy called leo Gura actualized
not net he explains a lot of like very
in depth like mmm-hmm like buddhism
slash in neuroscience
meditation stuff I like a lot of like
theory and philosophy and like holistic
psychology and I do admittedly something
could I spend a lot of time on is the
people who channel I don't know if
you've ever heard of this but people who
I'm not saying that I fully believe or
stand by them or know exactly what's
going on but it enthralls me I'm so
interested by it because the information
they say but it's these people who like
they're like I channel so I channel raw
from the planet blah blah blah and
they're like normal people and you watch
them on YouTube and they have whole
conventions and they'll be they'll like
kind of change their voice and they'll
essentially channel like some thing and
they'll say like what they're saying if
you wrote it down in like a book it's
like oh this is great information this
is like how people deal with their
emotions and it's great advice
I admittedly fall I watch a lot of that
stuff but not because I again not
because I'm like I believe this to be
hundred percent true mmm but because I'm
able to get the information I need out
of it or the judgment like it's just
it's it's interesting it strikes me as
very intriguing to think that like I
don't really know for sure but maybe
these people are experiencing that right
so yeah the channeling entities that's
like mine most like the deep dive where
I like what is really watching and it's
it's me it's is like this old lady who's
like I'm Karen but I'm gonna channel the
three so-and-so's and she's like me and
I talking come on yeah but it's like
then she'll say like ten minutes of like
read as if she's reading from like
Buddhism texts of like compassion about
humans and it'll be like whoa that it's
profound whatever character you might
have just made up to get that point
across it's amazing I love learning
about it yeah yeah that's where I'm at
okay where you at would you like that
know what I've been really enjoying to
watch is how whatever this it's videos
of people and personating cops so
they're pretending they're cop and
rightfully like yeah there's people over
yeah this is like police footage of
these people getting arrested and so
these people like the last one I
watched was this young guy who this was
like his third time being arrested for
this but he got a car that looks similar
to a cop car got purchased lights you
know online got a fake badge he's he
looks like a cop you know police officer
and he pulls over people speeding and
gives them fake tickets and so this he's
doing this meanwhile a real cop drives
up and he's well-known he's been
arrested like three times for doing this
he's like what are you doing okay
and so I've been watching that there's
like a whole group of people in the
world that do this how serious is it is
it like do they like try to run and they
don't run they just get arrested usually
for whatever reason they have this weird
you know fixation of one to be a cop or
a firefighter or that's a weird but they
don't pursue it I guess or maybe like
maybe they fail the test or maybe they
failed and so now this is the best way
they can do it but yeah it's interesting
you should check it out what do you
search on what do you say what is that I
don't even know how it popped out but it
got into my algorithm that I just
clicked on the next 80 videos I saw yes
do I you know there's a lot of that
that's like vastly unhealthy because of
yeah in certain ways but honestly a lot
of it just allowing them to allowing
these all this data to figure out what
you like and kind of like suggest to you
like I mean you know you don't want to
waste your time totally but life is you
know that's a wonderful thing and
entertainment is awesome so it uh that
knows me well at this point you know
what would also add my favorite by by
far like I like I like YouTube more than
Netflix more than I don't even have a TV
or cable do you have a room for those
and you're putting a whole I mean it's
like me my bed my toilet and my little
laptop you should put like a hit game of
pop stuck it on your phone yeah you
should put like one of those little pops
like the holders on the wall oh nice I
do right there yeah because it'd be
close enough to where like look like
your TV almost you have a string hanging
down you're laying in bed it's just like
above you
good one back-and-forth keep the fan
yeah but yeah I love YouTube YouTube it
the my college basketball team that I
coached they make fun of me non-stop
what do you watch on YouTube tonight
watching today nerd yeah what else do
you catch yourself on eg like what I
watch it I watch a ton of podcasts so I
really enjoy watching podcasts I'm
fascinated by interviews so like back in
the day I was fascinated by like Howard
Stern or like Larry King or you know I'd
listen to like radio shows and then it
transformed into podcast which I think
podcasts are to me it's like it was
invented for me you know it's like I did
it saying it's so cool I love pot
because I'm shocked that they're free
I'm shocked that they create the amount
that they do that are so well done I am
a huge fan of podcast so I watch a ton
of podcasts on YouTube what else do i
watch I'm really like interested by
fighters so I watch a lot of UFC stuff I
don't know anything about it
but I just think that like the the work
that they put in and the way that they
like take care of their bodies and just
the fact that they want to get in a ring
and duel doubt with another professional
fighter easy nuts it's so crazy we were
talking about why I think we kind of
share like we're not super competitive
at least other people right in in those
like that that's almost like some some
of them do have a very competitive like
me versus you and that's how they like
fight really well and I think they do it
to their advantage but there's a lot of
those guys that I think that it's this
like way of Zen like I respect you
because you pushed yourself as a as a
person it's like the best of your
ability and I did the same thing so it's
really let's just actually see who like
I've shaved myself up to be the best
person I could be and you did the same
so this is a really good fight like it's
Rawling exciting yeah I think you're
100% right I think a lot of these guys
are probably more you know like their
temperament is probably more even than
even the average person like I think if
you you know like average Joe was at a
bar and then caught well maybe not Conor
McGregor he's a bad example because he
gets a bit of rest
all the time for a bunch of people but
maybe cowboy Cerrone you know if he's at
a bar with some average Joe if a fight
broke out the average Joe is just as
likely to get into that fight as a UFC
fighter the UFC fighters not only well
trained but they also have like a like a
respect for you know fighting in general
it's not like something they show off
it's like right it's like something it's
almost like them it'd be like the
equivalent of like someone who is really
really good at like playing the drums
it's like they're not just gonna go
around slapping every little object they
see just to hear is they're gonna
perform when it's time to perform they
want to they've want to be in front of
people that respect it and so I don't
know I just have I think that fighters
are fascinating people I think they have
a screw loose to want to get into the
ring and but they're also brilliant and
so that the dichotomy is interesting to
me
yeah do they fascinate me too I'm
totally I have a couple friends who have
been into like Brazilian jiu-jitsu in my
tie and stuff lately and just as
beginners right they they say like I
absolutely love it and it's something
that eventually I want to get into I'm
more but I really enjoy my own time when
it comes to workout and gyms and stuff
but eventually I would love to learn to
like I don't know if I really want to
fight anybody but I've it's being cool
just to know though they like if someone
put their hands on you you could you do
it yeah yeah you know I've always had
this like my upbringing has always part
of my ego armor like one of my like main
weapons of ego was like whatever I can
do to make sure that like my chest is
puffed out to where I want to be nice
but people won't fight me also because
this sort it's like a weird thing right
but it you know it I've seen plenty of
fights I've been in plenty of fights
Seagrove identify it's I've been in
plenty of fights yeah I've been I've
actually had I've been knocked
unconscious at my own event Wow yeah
I'll tell that story got that's alright
that's a fun one
not a fun one but
they're essentially I've mentioned these
on here before I used to throw like
illegal renegade raves
okay woods I remember these actually
yeah did you ever go to I didn't know it
wasn't my scene you know I was probably
dribbling a ball somewhere yeah you're
probably working on here things but but
essentially it towards the end of the
night people just super hammered it
turned into like people who weren't
there for the music and like the little
secret scene that we had going on it was
people there who heard about it who were
there to fight literally they they were
when the fights broke out it was like
this like crazy brawl like what's that
movie where it's like stay golden
Ponyboy the outsider so you remember
that movie no but hey I'm shaking my
head yes yeah anyway so it's it's one of
these crazy movie scenes essentially
people are just like throwing punches
and stuff I ended up I was just trying
to I was I've always been like strong
didn't want to I don't want to hurt
people but my go-to move is I could
choke people out
little did I know I was choking people
out totally in the worst way it was
terrible but really I've learned how to
choke people out differently now you
were doing in a dangerous way like choke
yeah cutting off their their ego died
probably yes absolutely are they dead
they didn't die but I choked out one guy
went down to the ground and his friend
saw from afar and running kicked me in
the face as we were on the ground and
then it like went to that we went to the
hospital and stuff afterwards and it
wasn't I was fine it was no like yeah
got like you know the MRI or whatever I
was but anyway fights are crazy though
so here's what I was going to round
about about fights is is if when you
look at fights when you see fights when
you especially know when you're not in
them like so even at that night I was
even drinking and stuff like I was I
wasn't like I'm not some badass in the
story by any means I was when you see
fights as a whole especially ones like
drunk people at a bar and a raver at
sums like event just a bunch of dummies
man like it's people who don't know how
to fight it's people who are like it's
not so different so far from the UFC you
see like even you know sometimes we see
on a world
like these dudes just out on the street
just slug and each other like these are
those are fighters me I'm like they're
not UFC fighters but those are not even
half as in real life a fight is just
dumb people doing dumb things who have
no idea how to fight in their punches
aren't landing correctly and people are
hurting their own selfs with their own
hands and it's just so silly it's you
know and I saw this video once in it
generally changed like because that was
always my move is like I'm strong so I'm
gonna I'm gonna I'm gonna go for the
biggest guy and try to choke him out and
that's weird mentality but even that
like I saw this video once of this bar
fight the student was just trying to end
it and so he picks up a dude and he just
slams him but the dude who he picked up
landed on his neck and he broke his neck
and this is like some like 10 second
clip of our fight I'm like did this guy
just went to prison forever likely
because he paralyzed or killed a guy or
whatever you know some fights fights so
that fighting is not even compared in
the same field to like you know more
time Brazilian UFC and like do those
those men are just you know art it's an
art form it's an art form right yeah
just a growing up fighting would make my
stomach hurt when I would see it like
you know at school there was always
fights and so you know think of walking
down the hallway all of a sudden two
guys are squaring up and they're about
to fistfight I would just instantly get
like oh I'm about to get sick like this
is not my world
he's weird it's it's so weird and I just
I don't think you're alone with that
feeling I think it's so many people that
definitely yeah so I I've never been in
a fight though so I don't know like what
it feels I could get punched in the face
it's it's you know it's funny like if I
was having the same conversation talking
about like fights that I've been in if I
was having the same conversation like
three years ago I probably would have I
would have said like yeah they were
stupid but I probably would've bragged a
little more yeah but realist we looking
at like I'm a 28 year old man all the
fights I've been in like they weren't
cool fights they weren't like worth it
they were all like over the dumbest
things that I wish I wasn't involved I'm
never like an antagonist I've just so
you're you like your stomach hurt
when you see five for some reason not
saying it's a great trait but I'm just
in I'm in it I'm like I could be the one
to help these people that'll convince
them that they don't need to fight yeah
and so I get myself involved in and I
don't do it as much anymore but it's a
weird thing like it's weird the you know
and we all have different reactions with
public events like that but you know
that feeling that when you're like wait
someone's fighting is crazy man like
it's like whoa oh yeah I mean people
were drawn to it for sure I mean like if
you're at a public event and there's
fight people don't like scatter they
like go there's a fight let's run over
there and watch we're so enthralled you
know we're so focused on it we think
it's so cool but it's not cool like the
party fights anyway like really the
fights at clubs and bars and you know
I've seen a lot of security guards take
out dudes
and I've seen I've seen you know the way
things work when you're the drunk one
and you are in the wrong like you get to
a point where like you know bouncers are
calm dudes but like they'll you up
and I've seen people get like they're
big dudes usually yeah big dudes in
their sober yeah right
and in that they'll take a lot but
there's some some times where I've seen
like I'm like dude you're gonna get beat
up and then think I got beat up so but
yeah fighting though it is so different
it's like night and day compared to
think you have see yeah I'd like I'm
really intrigued by Conor McGregor I
just think he's like a fascinating
person right and so just like watching
him train and watching hit like they'd a
UFC before every like big paper for you
event they have like I think it's called
UFC embedded on YouTube and it's like
you know they follow the fighters
leading up to the fight for like two
weeks or whatever and it's just a bunch
of behind the scenes stuff I totally
have a loss that I might want to check
yeah that's cool you know they dig Conor
has a fight coming up we fought last
night
oh yeah go 81 80 40 seconds oh damn
then we fight kennel boy okay Ronnie
okay totally any and you knocked him out
in 40 seconds it was it was a it was
nuts
well I just saw it on Twitter but oh man
I totally want to I mean it's like 40
seconds yeah
but it was weird to I you know I know
nothing about fighting but what I had
never seen before was Connor so that he
runs out like you know like a spider
monkey jumps and tries it like me I'm in
the first second and cowboy kind of like
takes it you know hit him in the
shoulder and they start like almost like
getting in a clinch and Connor uses his
left shoulder in the clinch and just
starts ramming it up into Cowboys nose
and shatters Cowboys nose by doing this
like three times and I'd never seen that
you think shrugging it ya like it was
like a really hard shrug and so there's
a bunch of memes going around now of
like this kid who's like doing this
weird like shoulder dance and they're
saying it's it's Connor but cowboy said
after the fight is like yeah during when
he was doing that left shoulder thing he
broke my nose and within like five
seconds that's so crazy yeah so then I
got try fighting with your nose broken
yeah so he's got some blood you know and
then Connor hits him with a leg kick in
the in the head and that like rattles
him and then basically just beats him up
for 20 more seconds dang I can't I'm
gonna watch that yeah Conor McGregor I I
really like him I actually have a lot of
homies who who idolized him
I'm so with I you know a lot of people I
gift a lot of his arrogant side but I
think that if you get too caught up on
his is what you make might call ego run
I think you miss out on what's really
going on I think that he is he has
turned his ego into a lion that walks
next to him and he's the master of it I
think Vicky he has figured out how the
human brain works more than a lot of us
have it comes across as cocky of course
or I really I I don't know a ton about
him though I just listen to him like a
lot of his clips I like the motivational
videos on YouTube like in the morning
all yeah
mixed with like music and Tony Robbins
and Les Brown all this stuff but so he's
in there all the time and fascinating
he's so great he you know what was
interesting is you know the last like
two years I think probably he's been
getting in a lot of trouble outside of
his sport he's been getting arrested
left and right for fighting at bar
you know cameraman walks up to him
asking a question it'll slap the camera
other hand and break the camera I gotta
write you know just stupid stuff and he
said that in the past week or two like
during his interview leading up to this
fight he said like even if right before
his last couple fights he was drinking
like the week of the fight like just not
like you doing things that guys who were
risking her life should be doing right
you know and so he said like leading up
to this fight he cut out all drinking
he'd never missed a workout he was
really really focused and his whole
persona was so different like at the
presser where they two fighters like
both get weighed to make sure they their
own weight and they go up against each
other so they can take photos like
holding their fists up normally that's
like a really edgy like you know fiery
situation it was really chill he shook
his hand put his fists up they they did
another handshake they left at the fight
when he knocked him out knocked him out
runs over to him kisses him on the
forehead his the Cowboys grandma comes
in the ring Connor goes in hugs through
guys grandma he was like really really
respectful wow he's like he's done a
full 180 from the last time I had seen
him so I'm interested to see what like
what plays out right dude that's so cool
you know I'm Barry I'm always like on my
Facebook and on my social medias I'm
always very loud like a you know kind of
I realized Jordan Jordan Peterson very
much what is once you say like pick up
the heaviest object you can and run with
it you know I really like encouraging
people to find their idols find their
mentors find their teachers find their
coaches whatever I think it's so cool i
I think more more younger people idolize
Conor McGregor even I think that it's
just cool to explain like you know our
perceptions of him because I get how the
media portrays him and how a lot of
times he does seem like this cocky
person and all these things but there's
I think there's a lot of benefit to like
kids using that same momentum where they
can like sometimes we need a little bit
of a blind dream or a blunt like vision
of like I can do it you know there's no
way the
be where he was if he was not a little
bit cocky right you know I mean or like
you you almost have to trick yourself if
you're nobody you know in Ireland and
you want to become world champion yeah
you have to yet no one else is going to
tell you that right you gotta you had
you got to trick yourself so he tricked
himself then he he probably went a
little too far gotten to some trouble
because he was his mindset was maybe a
little too over the deep end her deep
end and now he's kind of reeled it back
to where he's in that like safe space
again but he's a fascinating guy and I
think he's number one as far as
entertainment goes and like being able
to sell a fight and I mean he has his
Irish whiskey now proper 12 that was
making millions and millions of dollars
yeah he's a fascinating Jordan Peterson
by the way carnivore got it oh yeah yeah
yeah have you ever tried the Carbonite I
haven't but Rogen's doing it right now
he is I heard him mention it on
something but I haven't consumed a ton
of joe lately have you as he said like
how it's been going for him yeah he said
it's he feels phenomenal but he has
explosive diarrhea oh wow yeah like he
said his veggies help you fiber he was
saying that he thinks he's getting a
diarrhea because I'm sure people are so
fascinated by this but he thinks he's
getting the diarrhea because his body's
like trying to figure out what he's
doing it's like oh crap where's all the
carbs you know like and so normally he
would have I'm probably saying that's
all wrong but his body would break down
the food differently and so now that
he's just carnivore just meat his body
doesn't know what to do with it right
yes oh yeah he said it but he said the
one big thing that he's really loving is
there's no drop-off in energy throughout
the day yeah definitely yeah I could see
that I'm trying to think because because
I would love to try carnivore
I like 30-day things I like I love
exploring to see what my body does very
in tune with my mind and body now so I'm
a weird sentence I know but I just like
I'm like okay that goes well with me
that doesn't go well right I'm not gonna
have it anymore you know I want the
for my body so I whole xxx is very great
my mental focus and I don't have any
sort of crashes my stomach is totally
fine
but I think a lot of us he was saying I
know it's a little lucky to talk about
poop but it's a real thing we all have
he was saying he had diarrhea I think
that so many people when they
dramatically switched the diet like the
first few days your body does this crazy
detox thing yeah on whole xxx they talk
about they have every single day you can
go to like her Instagram or in the book
or all these places and she'll be like
day two here's what you're gonna be
feeling and it's like this exclamation
you're like dude I feel that and yeah my
head hurts
and whenever when we eliminate these
things that we've been used to having
since we were kids man like down to the
formula down to the the packaged apples
the fruit snacks the drinks like
everything that we've always been having
in the Western world is full of like
sugar and all these added things so I
think that anybody's body reacts pretty
crazy the first few days whether it's
the first couple weeks or whatever but
it's I think that getting through that
with when it comes to like the diets is
important like not letting that be like
dude my body's a lot of whack
something's wrong here right it's more
like it's gonna suck for a couple days
at the beginning or maybe it's a couple
weeks or maybe have explosive diarrhea
and you're just pooping meat whatever is
happening with him but yeah getting
through that first like that draining
period that this that getting it out you
know you've been doing it for a while
right I think he's doing a month I think
he's I think he's doing a month year
he's gonna like check it out but what
what uh but I was actually gonna ask you
this earlier what a setup in your life
makes your body feel the best like sleep
food mmm you know anything exercising
anything in that world what if you
wanted your body to feel the best for a
week what would you do and okay so I'll
give I'm doing pretty good right now so
I'll talk about like my like ideal
schedule sort of as it goes so waking up
so I usually go to sleep I try to go
before midnight
and so there's intentionality there
so I'm not just gonna cover food here so
tension ality was sleep of like if I
tell myself I need to go to bed before
midnight because I'm waking up at a
certain time it's not like I want to
finish 30 more minutes of this show so
I'm stirring on my sleep so I start with
that I don't land my phone and get our
mess up yeah yeah all day okay good yeah
you made it sound like you were you had
it like on oh no oh no no no I don't
have it on my okay okay so but my ideal
day and I want to start it with tonight
so yeah I would say again I do have a
dreamy cushy life up here and I don't
really have to interact with the outside
world exactly when I'm like traveling
for tour for audio engineer stuff so
like I can have five days where I
literally don't talk to you but if
you're not podcast scheduled so I'm
pretty spoiled like I can have like a
very exact don't have to have Tupperware
with me and all these diet things but so
I wake up and I fast pretty much every
day fasting seems to work for me really
well I do intermittent fasting so I
stopped eating at like 10:00 or 11:00 at
night whatever and then I just add 12 to
14 hours the next day like sometimes if
it's just like 12 and a half or 13 hours
and I'm like pretty hungry it's starting
to make me lose focus
I'll eat but usually 12 14 16 hour fast
I'm not a Nazi about it I'm just
learning whatever I feel feel good about
so then I eat I break my fast with like
meal today I had steak hash browns and
Oh bacon
I meditate in the morning and I do yoga
that keeps me feeling pretty pretty Chi
my my daily meditations I usually do 10
minutes as my it's my minimum but I
don't push that too often I'm not like I
need to make sure I try to get 20 or 30
but 10 minutes is fine like sometimes I
just get 10 minutes for 10 days in a row
you know so wake up do tables app I use
an app I primarily use waking up by Sam
Sam Hanna and that's not advanced
advanced is not the word I want to use
at all but I think for anybody who
hasn't done any meditation where you
want to form a habit it's great
actually you know what I want to back up
it is a great app all around I would
actually suggest it to most people
because it teaches you a lot about like
you can listen to lessons on it and then
he'll he'll talk for 22 minutes about
the subjects or about meditation or he
has like other meditation teachers come
on he has two hour-long conversations
with them so those are on the app but I
use so 10 minutes a day on the app and
then meet me personally just because
again I have the most amazing life and I
I work really well when I smoke so then
I smoke after I meditate usually so
ideally it's before 8 a.m.
ok before 8 a.m. and then so so for me
as long as I'm able to be creative and
I'm like again I'm not like doing
something that needs to be super
corporate and I need to like have some
sort of like video call meeting at like
10 a.m. or something but so for me I'll
smoke after I meditate and then we're
talking about a joint the smoke out of a
bomb yeah smoke weed yeah yeah that's
that's what I was talking about in this
mocha Sircar cigar 8:00 a.m. I mean it
sounds weird to smoke weed in a damn
cigar Pepsi Pepsi essentially a fasting
whole 30 so kind of a more Paleo diet
daily meditation daily yoga and then
honestly I'm very very much a believer
of the content you feed yourself is is
is how you feel - like I'm talking
content like if there's people in your
life that are like lychee and they text
you every day in lychee I mean just not
lychee say like negative or they're just
sharing like drama new likes it also
gossip you know those I'm very like you
know just slicing I'm just like
trying to get that negativity away from
me and you don't come at me so and then
yeah essentially I feel like those are
like the huge things I guess I didn't
summer enjoy as well but lift weights so
as far as my workout plan my yoga
is a lot of like I'll be working for an
hour and I will get up and like still be
listening to whatever I'm doing and I'll
be like stretching and doing kinda like
freestyle yoga I'm all lay out my mat
right there for like 5-10 minutes and
I'll do that a couple times throughout
the day some days I'll do have like a
30-minute session and for that yoga I'm
not like a super professional yoga
person I'm not like amazing in all the
poses I just pulled something on YouTube
and follow it yoga with Adriene like
she's super great she has 30 day yoga
things that are she has 30 day yoga
things that you can follow hmm as far as
I'll show you on the way outside I shoot
a couple basketball hoops fairly often
just to like get active but I have a gym
outside too just in the garage I've got
a weight bench out there I'm really big
on pull-up and hang I I don't know
there's a lot of like back work that I
feel like I neglected doing I've just
been like I'm always working out and
stuff since high school so a lot of like
hangs and pull-up stuff I enjoy seems
like really stretched yeah I do some in
my backyard I do some high-intensity
interval training
my ideal workout I'll end with this my
ideal workout when I'm like feeling
shitty and I need to get better and I
need to like this is my like let's say
put my superhero cape off right get in
check I'm not having a great day but
let's push this out we go outside
and I put on some sort of motivational
thing and I'll do 15 minutes of yoga
stretching movement around and then as
soon as I fifteen minutes is over I go
on to the next of four things so I'll do
either weight lifting right there for 15
minutes so like curls bench pull-ups
just movement 15 minutes motivational on
or high-intensity interval training
which I'll do like five back and forth
in the backyard and that it's kind of
like you have 15 minutes here to like
get these five back and forth done
things yeah and then and then the last
thing usually is some sort of fun like
basketball is usually like but but it'll
be one of those like you can't stop
moving for 15 minutes at all so that's
kind of like my like my really fun
normal life person work out those four
things right
what about you that's good what's what's
your like like not not that you're
saying you're living it every single day
right but what would you say like
ideally if you yeah idea if I wanted my
brain and body to feel nice I would the
night before probably fall asleep at 11
p.m. which is very rare and before that
maybe from 10 15 to 11 I wouldn't have
any electronics going no laptop no
Instagram which is 99 percent rare this
is that impossible I would read is I
would be ideal if I was a smart person I
would do that every night and then I'd
wake up early probably 7 7 a.m. so I'd
be a good 8 hours there that'd be
perfect I'd be feeling good I'd have a
cup of coffee wouldn't eat I would do
the same thing intermittent fast how
about probably probably about noon I'd
probably play pick-up basketball
somewhere in there so probably like 8:30
a.m. I'd play pick-up basketball just to
get a good sweat I'd have a good salad
for lunch with all the fixin's all the
fixings yeah do you put a DiGiorno's
pizza on the salad or not if I wanted to
be happy okay yeah what if I liked
myself I like myself I I do like all the
little toppings on salad you know like
all the stuff that you wouldn't buy in a
store but you would get at a salad bar
you know that's what I want to try it
yeah all of it then I would I would do
something creative I feel like that is
when I'm happiest so I would be doing
you know and for me creative could be
coming up with a new basketball play
that I want my team to run that that
would fill that creative juice for me
and so do something creative for like
the next couple hours then I would coach
a team I get a lot of the joy out of
that and I think it allows me to get a
lot of my creative juices out also
and so to our practice there if I was
trying to feel good I would have a
weightlifting session after that and I
would I like short so I would go in for
30 to 40 minutes but I'm about that yeah
I'm all about shorter than short
workouts and then a really good dinner
maybe like a III I honestly do feel good
when I'm eating like a steak and some
vegetables and you know a glass of water
and some fruit and then entertainment or
fun and I had like a lot of alone time
so I probably watch YouTube or some
movies at night whatever YouTube
suggests yeah whatever yeah
cough impersonations yeah yeah whoever
is impersonating the cop whatever state
that's how I'm gonna watch that night I
do like a long time though hey which is
weird cuz I as a coach you're rarely
alone on the job but you said you like a
long time also okay yeah I feel like
it's for me it's the only way I can like
decompress and like get my energy back
yeah it's a lot of recharging is
recharged you know the introvert
personality type that's kind of a lot of
the defining factors is like just
because you're you can be an extrovert
knows you're great at people doesn't
mean that like when you get behind
closed doors it's not this like Ryan
let's get a little rest you know which
is funny because you're a DJ you know I
mean say like the life of the party yeah
I'm a coach so I'm surrounded by a team
your life and party too and then when we
go home we like being alone right yeah
and it's good to you know learn about
yourself and learn and let that be okay
to like you you know you end up saying
like me anyway I find myself saying no
to more plans which is fine Android
people are okay with that you know you
got to figure out like going out there
and giving everyone your energy is
amazing and it's worthwhile and it's is
you know something if you have the drive
to do it you can do it every day you
should but getting home to recharge and
take care of yourself so that next day
you're you can show up and be that best
person you know that's super important
that's that's never to be understated
I'm probably like most bummed away with
myself when I say okay to a plan
I don't really want to do I do that all
the time I do it all the time yeah I
just I hate bombing people out or like
saying no too often so if I've said no
to like a friend like four times in a
row good chance fifth time I'm gonna say
ass no matter what it is right right
and I always regret it as soon as I step
out the door but how does you want your
alone time interact with Shaylee it's
not too bad it's she's so cool man she
she understands me in different ways
like she a lot of times she'll be home
because she'll work three days in real
estate so she'll be nursing and so
should not nursing she's a nurse where
st. Peter's in Olympia okay Wow yeah so
so she drives an hour in the morning and
she works like 13 hour shifts or
something so it's like she drives an
hour in the morning and works her long
shift and he comes back and pretty much
goes straight to bed like when she comes
home I have like 15 minutes if we catch
up here about her day like I blah blah
blah yeah she tells me about all yes all
these just go to generally see diffs and
all this gross stuff but she and then
and then she'll go to bed so I have like
even sneaking up there you know it's
kind of different working from home like
so so on her day off though so she'll be
upstairs like she'll just be like
lounging or you know studying whenever
she's studying and there'll be some day
it's for like I don't go upstairs for
like eight hours except for like to get
a glass of water or something but there
is some days where I you know every two
hours I run up and not you know I'm able
to like give her a kiss or something and
come back down here so it's I get a lot
of my alone time I will say my mom is
living with us right now and that's like
it's wonderful you know it's my mom and
I'm glad that were able to help her out
but I do notice I it's funny I'm so
prissy and like I'll go upstairs and
I'll be thinking I'll be like listening
to something on my like three hours into
this chapter and I'm just thinking I'm
some genius monk on the mountains
learning this fascinating thing and then
you know my mom will just like want to
talk to me upstairs you know just I
can't won't say and I will of course
talk to her but I think mom I'm like
yeah
I'm learning about Buddhas on my own you
know and learning about this in-depth
subject like so she pulls me out but
yeah man it's being introverted with
Shaylee it's great because she
understands it is nice having her like
right upstairs we can go and interact
but like I said she doesn't like come
down here fairly often or she well from
time to time but for the most part she
understands that I like just happen my
own recharge yes we are getting fairly
up here in time I'm a friend I want to
make sure that we cover yeah I want to
make sure that people know that would
learn a little bit about roots and about
your coaching so if they need to learn a
little bit more about roots
how can you give the shout out like yeah
we're trying again yeah I mean you can
follow me on instagram at scott say pia
and that could lead you right to roots
roots is also at roots underscore sports
on twitter and at root sports on
instagram and yeah so we're gonna be
doing a bunch of basketball camps this
spring and summer that i'm looking
forward to and pretty much anything
basketball related in the calots county
area you should be coming to us
definitely agreed yeah and then also a
podcast yeah be coming from your corner
of the world yeah hoping to that would
be fun yeah and also if you want to come
check out a game in portland go to Lewis
& Clark College women's basketball team
definitely yeah heck yeah man
you know well you know I really
appreciate you coming on the podcast I
appreciate you coming by too and again
you know just exploring exploring the
wisdom that everybody has to teach in
the different perspectives you know
that's so this podcast is about mental
health because I believe that knowledge
is power I believe that just learning
and having conversation and learning how
people do things differently and in just
hearing your side and hearing about like
just amazing people who are just
following what they think they should be
doing and it's turning out well for them
and I'm grateful for you honor in our
community many shares roots appreciate a
big time I I love this community and I
look forward to giving back for as many
years as I'm alive excellent alright man
give me a fist bump
let's go junkyard love podcasts out
ethos DiGiorno's
Caressa daimyo Shibui Scott Scott
you